<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>The CleanCycle platform could significantly improve waste management efficiency and recycling participation. By digitizing reporting, scheduling, and tracking, cities could achieve up to 40% improvement in waste collection efficiency, reduce illegal dumping, and increase recycling rates by 25–30% within the first year of implementation. It would also create economic opportunities for local recyclers and informal waste collectors through better coordination and visibility. Data from the system could inform smarter city planning, reduce landfill pressure, and improve sanitation-driven public health outcomes for millions of urban residents.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Rapid urbanisation in cities like Lagos and Mumbai has led to overwhelming waste generation, with inadequate collection systems, poor recycling coordination, and limited data visibility. Many communities lack structured waste disposal routes, leading to clogged drainage systems, flooding, and public health risks. Informal recyclers and waste pickers, who play a vital role, often operate without digital inclusion or coordination. The challenge lies in connecting households, collectors, recyclers, and government agencies through a centralized, transparent, and data-driven system that promotes accountability, recycling efficiency, and sustainable urban cleanliness.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>CleanCycle - Smart Urban Waste &amp; Recycling Management Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The ideal CleanCycle solution would be powered by ServiceNow’s automation, integration, and workflow orchestration tools.</p>
<p>Key capabilities include:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Field Service Management: </strong>To schedule and track waste collection vehicles and recycling pickups.</li><li><strong>Flow Designer: </strong> To automate waste report routing and recycling request approvals.</li><li><strong>IntegrationHub: </strong>To connect with third-party IoT sensors, GPS trackers, and mobile apps for waste bin monitoring.</li><li><strong>Customer Service Management (CSM): </strong>To enable residents to log complaints, schedule pickups, and get updates.</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics &amp; Dashboards: </strong>To track collection efficiency, recycling rates, and environmental impact in real time.</li><li><strong>Mobile Agent: </strong>For field collectors and recycling partners to update progress and confirm pickups on the go.</li></ul>
<p>This system would enable real-time visibility, faster decision-making, and improved accountability across the entire waste management chain.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Integration with IoT sensors for smart bins and waste level monitoring.</p>
<p>Mobile and SMS gateway for citizen engagement in low-data areas.</p>
<p>GPS and mapping APIs (Google Maps) for route optimization.</p>
<p>Cloud infrastructure for scalable data storage and analytics.</p>
<p>APIs for recycling company systems to synchronize material tracking and payments.</p>
<p>Secure authentication (OAuth 2.0) to ensure safe data exchange between systems.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Key challenges may include data accuracy and participation, as public adoption requires awareness and consistent engagement. Integration with municipal systems might be complex, especially where legacy infrastructure exists. Connectivity and maintenance costs in low-income or high-density urban areas may also pose barriers. Additionally, behavioral change encouraging citizens to separate waste or report responsibly—requires sustained education campaigns. Lastly, ensuring data privacy and regulatory compliance when handling environmental and community data will be critical to maintaining trust and system integrity.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-30 15:43:14</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>d85976d3c3383210d7441933e40131cd</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>CleanCycle - Smart Urban Waste &amp; Recycling Management Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_d85976d3c3383210d7441933e40131cd</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-30 15:43:16</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
