<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>By automating disaster prediction and early warning, nonprofits and local governments could:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Reduce disaster response time</strong> by up to 60% through real-time alerts.</li><li><strong>Protect lives and assets</strong> by warning communities before extreme weather events occur.</li><li><strong>Empower NGOs</strong> with accurate, data insights to allocate resources efficiently.</li><li><strong>Strengthen resilience</strong> in climate-vulnerable regions using predictive technology.</li></ul>
<p>In measurable terms, EcoAlert System could help thousands of people from being caught unprepared each year and reduce property and crop losses through proactive risk management.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Communities around the world face increasing threats from environmental disasters such as floods, landslides, and extreme weather events. Many local nonprofits, councils, and disaster response teams lack real-time tools to monitor environmental risks or send timely alerts.&#13;
&#13;
As a result:&#13;
&#13;
Early warning signs often go unnoticed,&#13;
Communication with vulnerable populations is delayed,&#13;
Response efforts become reactive instead of preventive.&#13;
&#13;
This leads to avoidable loss of lives, property, and agricultural damage, especially in under-resourced or rural areas where manual monitoring is still common.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>EcoAlert System – AI Powered Environmental Disaster Prediction &amp; Early Warning System</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>EcoAlert System</strong> would be a <strong>ServiceNow powered AI automation platform</strong> that integrates environmental data (such as rainfall, river levels, and temperature) from <strong>public APIs</strong> and triggers early alerts to the relevant stakeholders.</p>
<h4><strong>How It Works:</strong></h4>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>Data Ingestion:</strong> ServiceNow pulls data from weather APIs (e.g., OpenWeather, Copernicus, or UK Met Office).</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>AI &amp; Predictive Intelligence:</strong> Machine learning models detect risk thresholds (e.g., flood likelihood, high wind speeds).</p>
</li><li>
<p>Workflow Automation:</p>
</li></ol>
<p>Automatically creates an incident or “alert record.”</p>
<p>Sends notifications via email, SMS, or chatbot to NGOs and community responders.</p>
<p>4. <strong>Dashboards &amp; Reports:</strong> ServiceNow Performance Analytics visualizes current risk areas and trends over time.</p>
<p><strong>ServiceNow Products / Capabilities to Use:</strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>App Engine:</strong> to build the EcoAlert System application and workflows.</li><li><strong>Flow Designer:</strong> to automate data triggers and alert notifications.</li><li><strong>Predictive Intelligence:</strong> for AI based pattern detection and disaster prediction.</li><li><strong>IntegrationHub:</strong> to connect with external weather and GIS APIs.</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics / Dashboards:</strong> to monitor alerts and visualize trends.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>External Weather and Environmental APIs</strong> (e.g., OpenWeatherMap, NASA Earth Data, or Met Office API).</p>
<p><strong>SMS or Notification Service Integration</strong> (e.g., Twilio, WhatsApp API, or ServiceNow’s Virtual Agent).</p>
<p><strong>Geospatial Mapping Tools</strong> (optional) for displaying affected areas visually.</p>
<p><strong>Cloud Hosting / ServiceNow Instance Access</strong> for real time processing.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>Data Accuracy &amp; Coverage:</strong> Public weather APIs may not always offer high resolution data for remote regions.</p>
<p><strong>Integration Complexity:</strong> Connecting multiple external APIs and ensuring consistent data formatting.</p>
<p><strong>Model Training:</strong> Developing accurate AI thresholds for predicting floods or storms requires historical data.</p>
<p><strong>User Adoption:</strong> NGOs and local governments may need training to interpret alert dashboards effectively.</p>
<p><strong>Connectivity Issues:</strong> In rural or disaster affected areas, lack of internet or mobile access may delay alerts.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-27 12:56:06</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>b6cfae9683307610eb5fa4d0deaad3f4</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>EcoAlert System – AI Powered Environmental Disaster Prediction &amp; Early Warning System</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_b6cfae9683307610eb5fa4d0deaad3f4</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-27 12:56:07</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
