<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>no</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cultural Preservation</strong>: Save thousands of life stories annually, creating permanent digital archives of family and community history.</p>
<p><strong>Therapeutic Benefits</strong>: Improve mental health outcomes for elderly and terminally ill patients through purposeful storytelling activities, reducing depression by 25-40%.</p>
<p><strong>Family Connection</strong>: Strengthen intergenerational bonds as younger family members engage with elders&#39; stories, improving family relationships and understanding.</p>
<p><strong>Healthcare Support</strong>: Provide care facilities and hospices with structured tools for memory therapy and patient engagement.</p>
<p><strong>Community Building</strong>: Create shared cultural repositories that preserve local history and connect community members across generations.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Generational Knowledge Loss Crisis: Every day, invaluable life stories, family histories, and cultural wisdom disappear forever when elderly individuals pass away. Key challenges include:&#13;
&#13;
Lost Heritage: 70% of family stories are never recorded, creating permanent gaps in family history&#13;
Social Isolation: Elderly individuals in care facilities lack meaningful engagement and purpose&#13;
Therapeutic Gaps: Healthcare providers need better tools to support mental health through storytelling therapy&#13;
Grieving Process: Families struggle to process loss without preserved memories and wisdom&#13;
Cultural Erosion: Communities lose historical knowledge and traditional practices with each generation</problem_statement>
        <project_name>MemoryKeeper – Digital Legacy &amp; Life Story Preservation Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>ServiceNow Platform Components</strong>:</p>
<ol><li><strong>Service Portal</strong>: User-friendly interface for story recording, family collaboration, and memory browsing</li><li><strong>Knowledge Management</strong>: Organize and categorize life stories, wisdom entries, and family histories with powerful search capabilities</li><li><strong>Workflow Engine</strong>: Automate story review processes, family notifications, and memorial creation workflows</li><li><strong>Case Management</strong>: Track individual legacy projects, family collaboration progress, and therapeutic goals</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics</strong>: Dashboard showing engagement metrics, story completion rates, and therapeutic outcomes</li><li><strong>Mobile App</strong>: Simple mobile interface for elderly users to record stories and view family contributions</li><li><strong>AI/ML Capabilities</strong>: Generate personalized memory prompts and automatically transcribe voice recordings</li><li><strong>Integration Hub</strong>: Connect with healthcare systems, family tree services, and digital storage platforms</li><li><strong>Virtual Agent</strong>: AI assistant to guide users through story recording and provide conversation prompts</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p>No technical dependencies highlighted for this solution</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p>No particular challenges highlighted for this solution</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-26 18:47:36</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>154d368ec378f2100acfdd777d013140</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>MemoryKeeper – Digital Legacy &amp; Life Story Preservation Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_154d368ec378f2100acfdd777d013140</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-26 18:47:37</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
