<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>FloodBridge has the potential to transform flood disaster response and community resilience in Africa. By digitizing and automating early reporting, verification, and resource coordination, the platform could reduce emergency response time by up to 60%, enabling faster evacuation and aid delivery.</p>
<p>Communities would gain a reliable channel for help, responders would benefit from real-time visibility into incidents and resources, and donors/NGOs would see improved transparency and accountability. Over time, the data collected could inform predictive insights for disaster preparedness, supporting smarter infrastructure planning.</p>
<p>In measurable terms, the solution aims to assist thousands of households per flood season, ensure equitable aid distribution, and significantly enhance coordination among government agencies, volunteers, and humanitarian partners. </p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Flooding in many African countries, especially Nigeria, often leads to displacement, infrastructure damage, and loss of livelihoods, yet response efforts remain slow, fragmented, and poorly coordinated due to limited data visibility, weak communication, and low digital infrastructure. FloodBridge seeks to address these challenges by providing a ServiceNow-powered platform that enables communities to report flood incidents through SMS, WhatsApp, or web forms; automatically verifies and prioritizes these reports; and connects them to available resources such as rescue teams, shelters, and volunteers. The platform integrates mapping, triage automation, and donation tracking to streamline communication between responders, local authorities, and NGOs, ensuring real-time visibility, faster decision-making, and transparent aid distribution — all optimized for low-connectivity environments common across African communities.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>FloodBridge - Community Flood Response &amp; Recovery on ServiceNow</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The ideal FloodBridge solution would leverage ServiceNow’s power to orchestrate workflows, automate actions, and connect stakeholders on a single platform.</p>
<ul><li>Incident Management &amp; Service Catalogue: Capture and track flood reports and aid requests.</li><li>Flow Designer: Automate triage, notifications, and task assignments for responders.</li><li>IntegrationHub: Connect to external channels such as WhatsApp, SMS, or GIS mapping APIs.</li><li>CMDB / Asset Management: Maintain a live registry of shelters, rescue boats, and volunteer teams.</li><li>Agent Workspace &amp; Mobile App: Allow verifiers and field teams to confirm incidents and update status remotely.</li><li>Performance Analytics &amp; Dashboards: Monitor response metrics, resource allocation, and community impact in real time.</li></ul>
<p>This combination of ServiceNow capabilities would create a coordinated, transparent, and data-driven emergency response system tailored to the realities of flood-prone communities in Nigeria and across Africa.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>The proposed FloodBridge solution would rely on a few key technical dependencies to function effectively. These include:</p>
<ul><li>Integration APIs: To connect ServiceNow with external data sources such as GIS/flood mapping APIs (e.g., GoogleMaps), SMS gateways, and WhatsApp Business APIs for community reporting.</li><li>Cloud Infrastructure: ServiceNow’s cloud platform for workflow orchestration and data management, plus potential integration with cloud storage (e.g., AWS or Azure) for storing geospatial and incident data.</li><li>Connectivity Layer: Stable internet or mobile data access for responders, along with offline or low-bandwidth support features to accommodate rural or flood-affected areas.</li><li>Authentication &amp; Security: Use of OAuth 2.0 or similar protocols for secure integration between ServiceNow, third-party systems, and mobile applications.</li><li>Mapping &amp; Geolocation Services: Dependency on Google Maps or Mapbox APIs for real-time visualization of affected areas and resource locations.</li></ul>
<p>These dependencies ensure seamless data exchange, scalability, and operational reliability, allowing the FloodBridge platform to function effectively even in challenging field conditions.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Implementing FloodBridge may face several challenges. One major issue is data reliability, as reports from remote communities could be inconsistent or difficult to verify quickly during a flood emergency. Connectivity limitations in rural or disaster-affected areas could also hinder real-time updates from field responders. Additionally, integrating multiple external systems , such as SMS gateways, WhatsApp APIs, and mapping tools, may present technical and cost-related complexities. Ensuring data privacy and security while handling sensitive community information is another key concern, especially in compliance with local data protection laws. Finally, achieving strong stakeholder collaboration among government agencies, NGOs, and volunteers may require clear governance and continuous engagement to maintain coordination and trust.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-30 15:10:43</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>99c1765bc3f43210d7441933e401316c</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>FloodBridge - Community Flood Response &amp; Recovery on ServiceNow</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_99c1765bc3f43210d7441933e401316c</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-30 15:10:46</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
