<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>no</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A technology solution could significantly reduce forced labour by empowering at-risk individuals with personalized skills training, potentially lifting millions out of exploitation. For instance, AI-driven platforms could scale education to reach underserved populations, increasing employability and awareness of rights, which might decrease vulnerability by 20-30% in targeted communities based on similar reskilling initiatives. It could also enable nonprofits to detect early signs of forced labour through data analysis, streamline rescue and rehabilitation efforts, and generate economic benefits by fostering a skilled workforce. Overall, this could contribute to global efforts in reducing the 50 million people affected by modern slavery, while promoting ethical supply chains and long-term social stability.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Forced labour, which is basically a form of modern slavery, affects an estimated 27.6 million people globally, with perpetrators generating around $236 billion in illegal profits each year. Vulnerable populations, including migrants, low-skilled workers, and those in poverty, are often coerced into exploitative work due to limited access to education, job skills, and awareness of their rights. This challenge is intensified by global supply chains that hide exploitation, the lack of scalable training programs, and insufficient resources for nonprofits and governments to intervene effectively. Traditional education methods fail to reach those individuals most at risk in remote or underserved areas, causing cycles of vulnerability and hindering lifelong learning opportunities that could empower people to secure fair employment.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>SkillShield Program - AI-Empowered Learning Initiative to Eradicate Forced Labour</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The ideal solution is an integrated AI-powered platform that uses generative AI to deliver personalized lifelong learning programs, helping individuals build marketable skills and escape forced labour cycles. Nonprofits or governments could use it to identify at-risk populations, then provide tailored educational modules on vocational skills, digital literacy, and rights awareness. </p>
<p>ServiceNow products or capabilities used would be:</p>
<p>Now Assist: To create personalized learning paths, chatbots for user guidance, and automated content generation in training modules. </p>
<p>Predictive Intelligence: Machine learning to analyze user data and predict vulnerability risks, prioritizing high-impact interventions.</p>
<p>Platform Analytics: To monitor dashboards in real-time, reporting and performance insights.</p>
<p><br />Workflow Studio and App Engine: To build custom workflows for program management, such as tracking learner progress, integrating with external NGOs, and automating reporting for nonprofits.</p>
<p><br />AI Agent: For interactive support in low-literacy environments, using conversational AI to deliver skills training via mobile or web interfaces, and also providing reply recommendations. </p>
<p><br />ServiceNow AI Platform: Overall foundation for seamless data integration and AI-driven insights, tailored for nonprofit scalability.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Secure APIs for integrating external data sources, from various databases on forced labour statistics or learning content from educational platforms.<br />Cloud infrastructure for hosting AI models and ensuring mobile accessibility in remote areas.<br />Data privacy compliance tools to handle sensitive user information from vulnerable populations.<br />Partnerships with device providers or internet services for low-bandwidth deployment in developing regions.<br />Machine learning datasets for training AI on forced labour indicators, potentially sourced from ethical, anonymized nonprofit repositories.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Data Privacy and Ethical Concerns: Handling sensitive data on exploitation victims could raise privacy risks; ensuring AI avoids biases (e.g., against certain ethnic groups) would require rigorous auditing.<br />Access and Digital Divide: Many affected by forced labour lack reliable internet or devices, limiting reach; solutions might need offline modes or community hubs.<br />Integration and Scalability: Linking ServiceNow with diverse nonprofit systems could face compatibility issues, and scaling AI training globally might strain computational resources.<br />Adoption and Trust: Building trust in AI among skeptical communities, plus training nonprofit staff on the platform, could slow rollout.<br />Regulatory Hurdles: Compliance with varying international laws on AI and labour rights might complicate deployment, especially in high-risk countries.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-16 13:36:21</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>f219027253687210a9c8d7f0a0490e83</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>SkillShield Program - AI-Empowered Learning Initiative to Eradicate Forced Labour</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_f219027253687210a9c8d7f0a0490e83</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-16 13:36:23</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
