<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li style="text-align: justify;">GreenTrade connects verified eco-conscious producers with global buyers through a transparent, traceable, and sustainability-certified digital marketplace.</li><li style="text-align: justify;">Producers can upload their product data, receive sustainability scoring such as fair-trade, organic, and access simplified export documentation.<br />Buyers can verify authenticity, source responsibly, and view sustainability analytics before making purchases.</li><li style="text-align: justify;">This system helps reduce exploitation, ensures fair pricing, and promotes environmentally responsible trade practices.</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Small-scale farmers, artisans, and local producers in developing regions often face barriers to entering international markets. They lack export certifications, sustainability verification, digital presence, and logistics support. As a result, their products are undervalued, leading to income inequality and unsustainable trade practices that harm both people and the planet.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>TradeFlow - Smart Export Management Hub for SMEs.</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>App Engine Studio -</strong> build the producer registry, product catalog, and export certification workflows.</p>
<p><strong>IntegrationHub - </strong>connect to global trade APIs, logistics providers, and sustainability certification bodies.</p>
<p><strong>Supplier Lifecycle Management (SLM) - </strong>manage producer onboarding, vetting, and ongoing compliance.</p>
<p><strong>Flow Designer - </strong>automate verification and export request approvals.</p>
<p><strong>Performance Analytics - </strong>monitor trade volume, sustainability ratings, and fair-trade compliance trends.</p>
<p><strong>Customer Service Management (CSM) - </strong>provide producers with multilingual export guidance and buyer support.</p>
<p><strong>Now Mobile - </strong>enable small producers in rural areas to register and track their export progress from mobile devices.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>APIs for trade documentation (customs, logistics, sustainability certification).</li><li>Secure cloud storage for product and certification data.</li><li>Integration with payment gateways and digital wallets.</li><li>Translation and localization tools for multilingual markets.</li><li>Blockchain or PKI-based verification for authenticity.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Standardizing diverse sustainability and trade certification frameworks.</li><li>Ensuring equitable access for rural producers with limited digital literacy.</li><li>Maintaining buyer trust and data transparency.</li><li>Managing export regulations across countries with different trade laws.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-24 23:13:05</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>208525a193f876101ec27ee32bba1046</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>TradeFlow - Smart Export Management Hub for SMEs.</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_208525a193f876101ec27ee32bba1046</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-24 23:13:06</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
