<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li>BioBank Connect envisions a unified, secure and intelligent digital registry for organ donation and transplantation management.</li><li>It enables hospitals to register donors and recipients digitally, capturing essential medical compatibility details such as blood type, organ type, and geographic proximity.</li><li>Integration with authorized medical databases ensures authenticity and compliance with healthcare standards.</li><li>Automated alerts notify hospitals and transplant coordinators when a match is found, reducing human delays.</li><li>Families receive transparent communication and consent tracking, ensuring ethical and timely processes.</li><li>Over time, the system can analyze donor trends, improve national organ donation rates, and save countless lives through faster matching and reduced wastage of viable organs.</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Organ donation and transplantation processes remain largely manual in many countries. Hospitals, NGOs, and government bodies maintain separate databases, often leading to mismatched or delayed donor-recipient connections. In urgent cases, this fragmentation can mean the difference between life and death. Moreover, the lack of transparency and public awareness discourages potential donors from registering.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>BioBank Connect: Organ Donation Registry</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>App Engine Studio: Build the registry application to capture donor and recipient details, manage hospital records, and track donation status.</p>
<p>IntegrationHub (Health APIs): Connect with national health databases, blood banks, and transport networks for real-time data sharing.</p>
<p>Flow Designer: Automate the donor-recipient matching logic, approval routing, and alert notifications.</p>
<p>Performance Analytics: Monitor donation rates, average match times, and success metrics to inform healthcare policy improvements.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p>No technical dependencies highlighted for this solution</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p>No particular challenges highlighted for this solution</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-29 07:30:12</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>953f77fac3f8b6106f772925990131d1</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>BioBank Connect: Organ Donation Registry</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_953f77fac3f8b6106f772925990131d1</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-29 07:30:13</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
