<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Today, it’s all about platforms like Instagram and Facebook — but there are still many talented people who aren&#39;t active on these platforms.<br />This small idea can be transformed into an app, where users simply register themselves and get opportunities to contribute to community events and shows.<br />Technology can help bring all this talent together in one place, making it easier to organize and run events with local or lesser-known contributors</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Sometimes, it’s not possible for everyone to bring in a popular star, MC, host, or someone who can drive the event and run the show with a full setup&#13;
This idea is more about bringing hidden or local talent together — creating a platform for them to shine, even with limited resources</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Hidden Talent</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p>No ServiceNow Products listed for this solution</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>I don&#39;t think so. The only point is that this must be available offline as well, so people can view and book the local talent without needing the internet</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p>No particular challenges highlighted for this solution</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-17 11:13:56</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>59afba0393e47a106304bd6cebba109e</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Hidden Talent</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_59afba0393e47a106304bd6cebba109e</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-17 11:13:58</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
