<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p class="p1">GreenTrack 360 would be a centralised sustainability management platform built in ServiceNow, that allows organisations to</p>
<ol><li class="p1">Track emissions data across departments, sites, and vendors (Scope 1, 2, and optionally Scope 3 emissions)</li><li class="p1">Analyse trends and identify high-emission areas using dashboards and reports</li><li class="p1">Automate data collection via integration with IoT devices, vendor reports, or Excel uploads</li><li class="p1">Assign and monitor sustainability goals (e.g., reduce emissions by 20% by 2026)</li><li class="p1">Gamify sustainability efforts with rewards for departments achieving green goals</li><li class="p1">Generate compliance reports for ESG audits or regulatory needs</li><li class="p1">Trigger alerts/workflows when carbon usage crosses certain thresholds (e.g., IT asset overconsumption)</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<ol><li>Empowers organisations to <strong>take real action on sustainability</strong></li><li>Helps meet <strong>regulatory compliance and audit readiness</strong></li><li>Improves <strong>transparency</strong> for stakeholders and investors</li><li>Reduces <strong>operational costs</strong> by identifying inefficient systems or processes</li><li>Drives <strong>employee engagement</strong> through visible green initiatives</li></ol>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Many organisations struggle to track, measure, and reduce their carbon emissions across departments, assets, vendors, and daily operations. Data is often siloed, inconsistent, or manually collected, making it difficult to identify high-emission sources, ensure compliance with sustainability goals, or make data-driven decisions toward decarbonisation.&#13;
&#13;
There is a growing need for a centralised, intelligent, and automated way to monitor carbon footprints, especially with rising ESG (Environmental, Social, and Governance) pressures and stricter regulations globally.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>GreenTrack 360: Smart Emissions &amp; Sustainability Tracker</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p> </p>
<ol><li>App Engine Studio – to build custom apps and workflows</li><li>Flow Designer – for automation and alerts</li><li>Performance Analytics – to visualize sustainability KPIs</li><li>IntegrationHub – to integrate with third-party data sources (e.g., utility companies, IoT sensors, Excel files)</li><li>CMDB – to track emissions per asset/location</li><li>Surveys and Assessments – to capture manual data from users/vendors (Optional):</li><li>GRC / ESG Management – if licensed, for advanced reporting and risk frameworks</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>Access to reliable emissions data (manual or via integration)</li><li>IoT or smart meter integration (if automating from building/energy systems)</li><li>Admin access to App Engine Studio</li><li>Possible need for custom tables for emissions tracking, goal management, etc.</li><li>IntegrationHub spokes for data ingestion (or build custom integrations)</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>Ensuring data accuracy across sources and departments</li><li>Onboarding vendors to submit their emissions data (Scope 3)</li><li>Training internal users to use the platform and input data properly</li><li>Possible resistance to transparency if teams underperform on goals</li><li>Maintaining up-to-date regulatory requirements for reporting</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>TechTrekwithAJ</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-22 12:12:51</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>cd6bfc3447f07a90ec92d24b116d4310</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>GreenTrack 360: Smart Emissions &amp; Sustainability Tracker</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_cd6bfc3447f07a90ec92d24b116d4310</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>TechTrekwithAJ</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-22 12:12:52</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
