<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li>MediReach creates a transparent, digital network to track medical supplies from warehouse to clinic.</li><li>It automates expiry alerts, restock triggers and delivery confirmations through mobile access.</li><li>The solution ensures that critical medicines are available when needed, reducing waste and improving public health outcomes in underserved regions. </li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Rural healthcare centers frequently experience stock shortages or expired medicines because of poor tracking in the supply chain.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>MediReach: Rural Health Logistics Tracker</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The solution uses Field Service Management (FSM) for tracking deliveries, HAM for monitoring inventory and Flow Designer for automating restock workflows. IntegrationHub can connect with external ERP or logistics systems to ensure end-to-end visibility of supply chain health.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p>No technical dependencies highlighted for this solution</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p>No particular challenges highlighted for this solution</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-27 11:25:43</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>649e9edac3f0b2106f77292599013124</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>MediReach: Rural Health Logistics Tracker</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_649e9edac3f0b2106f77292599013124</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-27 11:25:44</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
