<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<h3><strong>Potential Impact of the Solution</strong></h3>
<h4>&#x1f9e0; <strong>1. Enhanced Community Cyber Safety</strong></h4>
<p>Creates a <strong>trusted local network</strong> for citizens to report and verify scams in real time.Reduces the spread of phishing, fraud, and misinformation through <strong>early detection and alerts</strong>.</p>
<h4>&#x1f4ca; <strong>2. Measurable Impact &amp; Value</strong></h4>
<p><strong>30–50% faster response</strong> to cyber incidents due to automated reporting workflows.<strong>Higher awareness</strong> — trackable via number of users educated through tips, alerts, and verified reports.<strong>Reduction in repeated scams</strong> in the same region through data-driven prevention.Transparent metrics: number of reports resolved, alerts issued, and citizens protected.</p>
<h4>&#x1f91d; <strong>3. Empowered Communities &amp; Collaboration</strong></h4>
<p>Builds a <strong>bridge between residents, cyber cells, and law enforcement</strong>, enabling coordinated action.</p>
<p>Encourages digital literacy and safe online behavior through gamified learning and reward systems.</p>
<h4>&#x1f310; <strong>4. Long-Term Sustainability</strong></h4>
<p>Over time, generates <strong>community-level cyber intelligence data</strong> that helps identify trends and high-risk zones.Promotes a <strong>self-sustaining ecosystem</strong> where citizens become active participants in cyber resilience.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Cyber scams are increasing at the community level — from fake text messages and phishing calls to fraudulent social-media ads. Most victims don’t know where to report such incidents or how to warn others nearby. Local law enforcement and cyber cells often receive fragmented data, making it hard to detect patterns or respond quickly.&#13;
&#13;
There is currently no centralized, community-driven platform to report, verify, and share alerts about local cyber threats in real time.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Local Cyber Watch app</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><h1>ServiceNow Products &amp; Capabilities</h1>
<p><strong>Experience &amp; Intake</strong></p>
<ul><li>
<p><strong>Employee Center / Service Portal (UI Builder)</strong> – public portal, report form, alerts feed, knowledge hub.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Now Mobile</strong> – quick report (camera upload), geo-alerts, push notifications.</p>
</li></ul>
<p><strong>Workflow &amp; Integration</strong></p>
<ul><li>
<p><strong>Service Catalog &#43; Record Producers</strong> – “Report a scam,” “Publish alert.”</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Flow Designer &#43; Subflows</strong> – intake → dedupe → scoring → triage → publish.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>IntegrationHub (REST/Webhooks)</strong> – inbound email/SMS, FB/WhatsApp, WHOIS/Google Safe Browsing/OTX/VirusTotal, ISP/Law-Enforcement intake.</p>
</li></ul>
<p><strong>Case/Partner Management</strong></p>
<ul><li>
<p><strong>Customer/Partner Service Management (CSM)</strong> – onboard partners, SLAs, collaboration cases.</p>
</li><li>
<p>(Optional) <strong>Field Service Management (FSM)</strong> – if physical outreach/poster campaigns or device pickup events are needed.</p>
</li></ul>
<p><strong>Analytics &amp; Intelligence</strong></p>
<ul><li>
<p><strong>Performance Analytics</strong> – dashboards (reports by ZIP, time-to-triage, alerts issued, repeats prevented).</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Predictive Intelligence</strong> – duplicate detection, anomaly/spam guard, hotspot prediction.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Knowledge Management</strong> – playbooks, scam tip sheets, “is this legit?” articles.</p>
</li></ul>
<p><strong>Trust, Security, Compliance</strong></p>
<ul><li>
<p><strong>RBAC</strong> for roles (community user/moderator/analyst/partner).</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Audit/history</strong> on alerts and evidence; retention policies; consent for contact data.</p>
</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><h3>Data model &amp; storage</h3>
<p>Tables for <strong>reports, indicators (IoCs), alerts, partners, distributions</strong>, subscriptions</p>
<p>Attachments (screenshots/voicemails); size &amp; retention limits</p>
<p>Geo fields (ZIP/city) for local targeting</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><h4><strong>Data Sharing &amp; Integration</strong></h4>
<ul><li>
<p>Connecting with multiple partners (ISPs, law enforcement, social media, threat-intel APIs) involves <strong>different data formats, permissions, and security standards</strong>.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Maintaining reliable integrations for inbound and outbound alerts requires strong API governance.</p>
</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-25 19:26:49</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>e2db75f9c3b432104b9c1c84e401316f</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Local Cyber Watch app</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_e2db75f9c3b432104b9c1c84e401316f</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-25 19:26:50</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
