<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul style="list-style-type: disc;"><li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ol><li>
<p>Accessible, self-service request submission for property modifications, maintenance, or barrier removal.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Real-time case tracking and communication, reducing response times and increasing satisfaction.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Centralized coordination for managers, technicians, and volunteers, improving operational efficiency.</p>
</li></ol>
</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>People with disabilities, including the visually impaired and those with mobility limitations, face significant challenges accessing and finding suitable housing or public facilities. Nonprofit organizations and property managers often lack coordinated digital channels to address individual accessibility requests, track modifications, or support timely maintenance. Current processes are fragmented—relying on calls, emails, or paper forms—and lack transparency, accessibility for users with disabilities, and end-to-end status tracking. The absence of tailored self-service, multi-language, and assistive technology support undermines independence and inclusion for these individuals.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Accessible Properties Helpdesk for Special Needs</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The solution is a ServiceNow Service Portal customized for accessibility, offering:</p>
<ol><li>
<p>Easy-to-use forms with screen reader support, voice commands, and adaptable color/contrast settings.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Multi-language support and mobile optimization for on-the-go access.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Automated workflow for routing requests to responsible staff, notifications, and escalation for urgent needs.</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Integration with third-party accessibility auditing and mapping platforms (API).</p>
</li><li>
<p>Support for assistive devices (screen readers, speech-to-text, Braille terminals).</p>
</li><li>
<p>Secure data storage and compliance with accessibility and privacy regulations (ADA, GDPR).</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Ensuring complete accessibility coverage for diverse disabilities and adaptive technologies.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Providing training and support for staff to use and administer accessible platforms.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Managing data security and privacy for sensitive individual information.</p>
</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-30 14:32:14</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>16f9a61793b0321097a53d6efaba10db</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Accessible Properties Helpdesk for Special Needs</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_16f9a61793b0321097a53d6efaba10db</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-30 14:32:15</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
