<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Develop a ServiceNow-based application called <strong>GreenBalance</strong>, designed to help authorities, organizations, and citizens calculate, track, and verify compensatory tree planting requirements.</p>
<p><strong>Tree Assessment Module:</strong><br />Users can log details of trees to be cut (species, height, trunk diameter, canopy size, location).<br />The app calculates the <strong>Compensatory Planting Ratio</strong> automatically using ecological formulas (e.g., 1 large tree &#61; 5 new saplings).<br /><strong>Afforestation Calculator:</strong><br />Based on tree size and species, it determines how many plants need to be replanted to balance carbon loss and green cover.<br />Includes a dynamic formula configurable by local forest department policies.<br /><strong>Mapping and Location Tracking:</strong><br />Integrates with Google Maps or GIS data to mark both <strong>deforested</strong> and <strong>reforestation</strong> sites.<br />Tracks where and when compensatory planting occurs.<br /><strong>Workflow and Approvals:</strong><br />Automates requests for tree cutting permits and ensures compensatory plans are approved before execution.<br />Tracks compliance through ServiceNow workflows.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Promotes sustainable development by ensuring every tree cut is properly compensated through replanting.<br />Helps maintain biodiversity and reduce carbon footprint.<br />Creates accurate digital records for environmental monitoring.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Enables forest departments and municipal bodies to <strong>track compliance</strong> with environmental regulations in real-time.<br />Reduces manual paperwork and corruption risks.<br />Provides transparent data for audits and environmental clearances.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Deforestation caused by urban development, construction projects, and infrastructure expansion leads to a significant loss of green cover and biodiversity. Although many governments mandate compensatory afforestation — the process of planting new trees to offset those cut down. this process is often poorly tracked and managed.&#13;
Currently, there is no unified digital system to calculate how many new trees need to be planted based on the size, species, and ecological value of the trees removed. Manual documentation and fragmented tracking lead to inconsistencies, delays, and poor accountability in afforestation initiatives.&#13;
In INDIA, Compensatory Afforestation is legal requirement</problem_statement>
        <project_name>GreenBalance: A ServiceNow Application for Compensatory Afforestation Management</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>Flow Designer</strong> – Automate approvals and notifications.<br /><strong>IntegrationHub</strong> – Connect to GIS, weather, or carbon offset APIs.<br /><strong>Service Portal / UI Builder</strong> – Build interactive dashboards and calculators.<br /><strong>Reporting &amp; Analytics</strong> – Generate compliance and impact reports.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>None we are going to use all OOB</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p>No particular challenges highlighted for this solution</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-27 19:15:49</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>0c1d40aac37832105b91be3ed4013113</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>GreenBalance: A ServiceNow Application for Compensatory Afforestation Management</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_0c1d40aac37832105b91be3ed4013113</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-27 19:15:50</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
