<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li>
<p><strong>Traceability:</strong> Increase percent of donations with verifiable end-to-end records from ~10–30% to <strong>&gt;90%</strong> in covered programs.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Leakage reduction:</strong> Detect and reduce financial/material leakage by <strong>30–60%</strong> in pilot regions within 12 months (through automated anomaly detection and mandatory verification steps).</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Reconciliation time:</strong> Cut reconciliation and audit preparation time from <strong>weeks/months → days</strong>, lowering administrative overhead by <strong>40–70%</strong>.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Donor confidence &amp; retention:</strong> Improve donor satisfaction metrics and repeat-donation rate by <strong>15–30%</strong> via donor-facing transparency dashboards and receipts.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Faster decision-making:</strong> Real-time dashboards reduce decision latency (time to identify issues) from days to <strong>minutes/hours</strong>.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>M&amp;E coverage:</strong> Increase percent of activities with photo/GPS-verified evidence from field operations from low baseline to <strong>&gt;85%</strong>, enabling accurate SDG mapping and reporting.</p>
</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Donations in the form of cash, goods, or services move through multiple hands — donors, NGOs, vendors, logistics partners, and field volunteers — yet visibility across the entire chain is weak.&#13;
As a result, funds are lost or diverted, distributions are duplicated, receipts can’t be verified, and donor confidence drops.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>AidFlow – Transparent Donation &amp; Relief Tracking Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>
<p><strong>App Engine Studio:</strong> to build custom donation, procurement, and beneficiary records</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Flow Designer:</strong> for automated workflows (donation approvals, status updates, audits)</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>IntegrationHub:</strong> to connect with banking/payment APIs, logistics systems, and ERP tools</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Now Mobile / UI Builder:</strong> for clean, mobile-friendly donor and field agent dashboards</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Performance Analytics:</strong> for impact metrics, SDG alignment, and fraud detection insights</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Document Management &amp; Attachment API:</strong> to store receipts, invoices, and verification photos</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Data Encryption &amp; Access Control Lists (ACLs):</strong> to protect sensitive donor and beneficiary data</p>
</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>
<p>APIs for financial transactions (bank, mobile money, or payment gateways)</p>
</li><li>
<p>Logistics or inventory APIs for shipment tracking (optional)</p>
</li><li>
<p>Optional blockchain or immutable ledger for high-trust audits</p>
</li><li>
<p>Offline data sync service for areas with poor internet connectivity</p>
</li><li>
<p>Map or geolocation services (Google Maps or OpenStreetMap) for site verification</p>
</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>
<p><strong>Connectivity:</strong> Field teams often operate with weak or no internet, requiring robust offline design.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Data Quality:</strong> Incomplete or inaccurate reports require strong validation and user training.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Adoption:</strong> NGOs are used to manual tools; onboarding and incentives will be essential.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Multi-party Coordination:</strong> Aligning donors, vendors, and NGOs on shared data standards takes time.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Privacy:</strong> Handling beneficiary data requires compliance with data protection laws and consent management.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Fraud Prevention:</strong> Fake photo or signature submissions must be mitigated via timestamps, GPS, and audit checks.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Sustainability:</strong> Post-pilot, long-term maintenance needs a sustainable funding or subscription model.</p>
</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-15 10:41:39</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>48b46ce2c3e8b210b202be3ed401314a</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>AidFlow – Transparent Donation &amp; Relief Tracking Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_48b46ce2c3e8b210b202be3ed401314a</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-15 10:41:40</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
