<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Respondr.AI is a multi-agent AI disaster response system built on ServiceNow that</p>
<h4>AI Agents (via Agentic AI Studio)</h4>
<ol><li>Serve as virtual disaster responders (AI Agents) that autonomously:</li><li>Assess incoming community needs (food, water, shelter)</li><li>Prioritise emergency cases using severity/context</li><li>Coordinate with human responders or automate workflows</li><li>Route critical tasks to local authorities or NGOs</li></ol>
<h4> Key Capabilities of Responder.AI :- </h4>
<ol><li>Accept incident reports from citizens via portal, mobile, or chat</li><li>Auto-classify and triage requests (e.g., medical, rescue, supply)</li><li>Use AI Agents to dynamically assign, escalate, or automate relief workflows</li><li>Generate community heat maps to visualise demand and supply zones</li><li>Send targeted alerts or instructions to affected populations</li><li>Track volunteer resources and match them to real-time needs</li><li>Launch mental health checks for impacted individuals post-disaster</li></ol>
<h4>Potential Impact will be :-</h4>
<ul><li>Faster disaster response using AI triage and intelligent task routing</li><li>Reduces chaos through centralised coordination</li><li>Increases survival rates and ensures resources go where needed most</li><li>Supports responders and NGOs with smart planning tools</li><li>Promotes community resilience and post-disaster recovery</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>During disasters (natural or man-made), communities often suffer from lack of real-time coordination, delayed response, and fragmented communication between responders, agencies, and the public.&#13;
&#13;
Critical needs like food, shelter, medical help, and evacuation updates often get lost in chaos. First responders are overwhelmed, and citizens are unsure where to go or who to ask. There’s no unified intelligent system to dynamically manage this crisis at scale.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Responder.AI – Intelligent Disaster &amp; Community Support Assistant</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>Agentic AI Studio – Deploy AI agents for dynamic triage and coordination</li><li>App Engine Studio – Build forms, dashboards, workflows for crisis reporting</li><li>Flow Designer – Automate common workflows (supply dispatch, alerts)</li><li>Virtual Agent / Mobile App – For citizen reporting and updates</li><li>Performance Analytics – Monitor trends, heatmaps, response KPIs</li><li>IntegrationHub – Integrate with weather APIs, emergency services, NGOs</li><li>CMDB / Location Tables – Map resources (shelters, hospitals, etc.)</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<p>Other which can be utilised :- </p>
<ol><li>Add <strong>AI Copilot for Volunteers</strong> to guide new responders</li><li>Use <strong>gen AI</strong> to summarise field reports and generate daily briefings</li><li>Predict future disaster impact zones using <strong>AI forecasting models</strong></li><li>Connect with <strong>crowdsourced data platforms</strong> (e.g., OpenStreetMap, WhatsApp updates)</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>Integration with external systems (e.g., weather data, emergency services)</li><li>Access to AI Agentic Studio (for AI-driven workflows)</li><li>Mobile interface or citizen portal</li><li>GIS/Mapping plugin (for real-time zone visualisation)</li><li>Data privacy measures for handling sensitive citizen info</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>Training AI agents to respond ethically and contextually</li><li>Managing data accuracy during fast-moving disaster events</li><li>Gaining public trust in AI-driven emergency response</li><li>Integrating across multiple government and relief organisations</li><li>Ensuring multi-language support and offline fallback for low-connectivity areas</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>TechTrekwithAJ</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-22 13:11:06</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>4ca8497047347a90ec92d24b116d43d1</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Responder.AI – Intelligent Disaster &amp; Community Support Assistant</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_4ca8497047347a90ec92d24b116d43d1</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>TechTrekwithAJ</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-22 13:11:07</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
