<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A skills exchange platform specifically for seniors would combat social isolation by creating regular interactions around meaningful contributions. Seniors could access services they need without financial burden by trading their own skills. The system would help them feel valued and purposeful by sharing their knowledge. Communities would benefit from seniors staying active and engaged. Healthcare costs could decrease as social connection improves mental and physical health for aging populations.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Retirees and senior citizens often feel disconnected and undervalued after leaving the workforce, despite having decades of valuable skills and knowledge. Many face fixed incomes and can't afford to pay for services they need like tech help, home repairs, or transportation. At the same time, they have skills others need such as tutoring, cooking, sewing, woodworking, or financial advice. There's no organized way for seniors to exchange services with each other based on skills rather than money, leading to social isolation and unmet needs.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>WisdomWorks Exchange - Local Skills Exchange for Seniors</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>Seniors would create profiles listing skills they can offer such as teaching languages, providing tech support, doing light gardening, giving music lessons, or sharing cooking expertise. They also list help they need like transportation, grocery shopping, yard work, or computer troubleshooting. The platform matches people who can help each other based on complementary needs. When someone helps another person, they earn time credits that they can spend requesting help from others. The system tracks these exchanges and suggests good matches. Community coordinators from senior centers could help less tech-savvy participants get set up. Group activities and classes could be organized through the platform to bring people together.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>ServiceNow Products/Capabilities used:<br />Service Catalog for browsing available skills and posting needs, Advanced Work Assignment to match seniors based on complementary skills and needs, Case Management to track each exchange request and completion, Knowledge Management for skill-sharing tutorials and guides, Performance Analytics to show exchange activity and social connection metrics, and Virtual Agent to help navigate the system through simple voice or text interaction. </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>The solution uses primarily native ServiceNow capabilities. A time credit tracking system would need to be built to record exchanges. The interface would need senior-friendly design with large text and simple navigation. Phone support or in-person assistance at senior centers would help participants who aren&#39;t comfortable with technology. Optional SMS notifications for those without computers.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Making the platform accessible for seniors with varying levels of tech comfort. Ensuring safety when seniors meet strangers for service exchanges. Balancing the time credit system fairly when different skills have different values. Managing situations where exchanges don&#39;t meet expectations. Building critical mass of participants so everyone can find good matches for their skills and needs.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-25 08:39:23</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>45a86be193307a104a52385efaba10aa</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>WisdomWorks Exchange - Local Skills Exchange for Seniors</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_45a86be193307a104a52385efaba10aa</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-25 08:39:24</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
