<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A centralized, automated platform would transform the way environmental NGOs track and share their progress.<br /><strong>Potential impacts include:</strong></p>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>Improved Transparency:</strong> Real-time dashboards showing impact metrics (e.g., trees planted, CO₂ offset, waste recycled).</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Data-Driven Decisions:</strong> Identify high-impact areas and optimize use of resources.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Volunteer Engagement:</strong> Allow contributors to log their efforts and visualize their personal impact.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Donor Confidence:</strong> Public-facing dashboards that demonstrate outcomes with credible data.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Scalability:</strong> A reusable ServiceNow solution that can be adopted by multiple nonprofits globally.</p>
</li></ol>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Nonprofit organizations working on environmental initiatives—such as tree planting, waste reduction, clean energy adoption, and pollution monitoring—struggle to track, measure, and communicate their impact efficiently.&#13;
Currently, most data is collected manually using spreadsheets, emails, or disconnected systems, making it difficult to:&#13;
&#13;
Consolidate and analyze field reports from volunteers&#13;
&#13;
Measure progress toward sustainability goals&#13;
&#13;
Report transparent results to donors and the community&#13;
&#13;
Optimize resource allocation across regions and projects&#13;
&#13;
This lack of visibility leads to data silos, inefficient decision-making, and reduced donor confidence.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Environmental Impact Tracker</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The ideal <strong>EcoTrack</strong> solution would be a <strong>ServiceNow-based platform</strong> that connects environmental projects, volunteers, and donors in one ecosystem.</p>
<p><strong>Core Features:</strong></p>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>Project Management Dashboard:</strong></p>
<ol><li>
<p>Create and manage environmental projects (e.g., “River Cleanup 2025”).</p>
</li><li>
<p>Define metrics (trees planted, waste collected, energy saved).</p>
</li></ol>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Volunteer Activity Logging:</strong></p>
<ol><li>
<p>Volunteers log activities via a self-service portal or mobile app.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Geo-tagging support for project locations.</p>
</li></ol>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Impact Analytics &amp; Visualization:</strong></p>
<ol><li>
<p>Real-time dashboards for tracking progress.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Charts showing CO₂ offset, waste reduction, etc.</p>
</li></ol>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Public Transparency Portal:</strong></p>
<ol><li>
<p>Public-facing page displaying verified impact statistics.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Integration with social media or websites.</p>
</li></ol>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Automation &amp; Notifications:</strong></p>
<ol><li>
<p>Automated alerts for milestone completion, inactivity, or data gaps.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Scheduled reports for management and donors.</p>
</li></ol>
</li></ol>
<p><strong>User Roles:</strong></p>
<ol><li>
<p>NGO Admin</p>
</li><li>
<p>Project Manager</p>
</li><li>
<p>Volunteer</p>
</li><li>
<p>Donor / Public Viewer</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Yes, a few dependencies may apply:</p>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>External APIs</strong> for weather, carbon footprint calculations, or location data.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Data integration</strong> from IoT devices or field sensors (optional).</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Access to Performance Analytics</strong> module for advanced reporting.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Public portal hosting</strong> if the transparency dashboard is made public-facing.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Volunteer authentication</strong> via SSO or simple self-registration</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p><strong>Data Accuracy:</strong> Ensuring volunteers and field teams submit verified and consistent data.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Integration Complexity:</strong> Connecting ServiceNow with external systems or IoT sensors may require custom APIs.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Adoption &amp; Training:</strong> Nonprofits may need onboarding support to use the platform effectively.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Cost Constraints:</strong> Smaller NGOs might face challenges with licensing or hosting costs.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Scalability:</strong> Designing the solution to handle multiple NGOs and thousands of entries efficiently.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Privacy &amp; Security:</strong> Protecting personal data of volunteers and donors while maintaining transparency.</p>
</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-23 10:32:54</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>cf7f298d8330f2109fe5c260ceaad325</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Environmental Impact Tracker</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_cf7f298d8330f2109fe5c260ceaad325</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-23 10:32:56</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
