<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p><strong>Potential Impact of the Solution:</strong></p>
<p>Our solution leverages ServiceNow’s powerful automation, workflow management, and security capabilities to help nonprofit organizations address critical operational and cybersecurity challenges. By centralizing sensitive data, automating routine processes, and proactively monitoring digital risks, nonprofits can reduce the likelihood of data breaches and operational bottlenecks.</p>
<p>The measurable impact includes:</p>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>Enhanced Security and Compliance:</strong> Minimized risk of data loss or breaches, protecting confidential information of donors, beneficiaries, and volunteers.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Operational Efficiency:</strong> Automated workflows reduce manual tasks, freeing staff to focus on mission-critical activities, increasing productivity and reducing errors.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Resource Optimization:</strong> By streamlining processes, nonprofits can save time and financial resources, allowing more funding and effort to go directly toward programs and community support.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Scalable Support:</strong> The solution enables organizations to handle increased operational demands without a proportional increase in staff or overhead.</p>
</li></ol>
<p>Overall, the solution empowers nonprofits to operate more securely, efficiently, and effectively, amplifying their social impact and enabling them to reach and support more people in need.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Nonprofits deal with sensitive donor and volunteer info, but most don’t have the tools or expertise to keep it fully secure. That leaves them open to cyber threats, data breaches, or compliance problems, which can hurt their reputation and take focus away from their mission. &#13;
We want to build a simple, smart way for nonprofits to protect their data, so they can focus on doing good without worrying about security.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>SafeDonor: Nonprofit Digital Risk Guardian</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>I imagine a Nonprofit Cybersecurity &amp; Workflow Hub built on ServiceNow that helps nonprofits stay secure and run smoothly. It’s like having a single dashboard where organizations can monitor cybersecurity risks and automate essential operations without juggling multiple tools.</p>
<p>Here is what it would do:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Automated Risk Detection &amp; Alerts:</strong> The system constantly scans for threats, misconfigurations, or suspicious activity and instantly alerts the team.</li><li><strong>Centralized Case Management:</strong> Every incident, whether it’s a security issue, operational problem, or volunteer request, is tracked and resolved in one place.</li><li><strong>Workflow Automation for Operations:</strong> Routine tasks like donor management, volunteer onboarding, or program reporting are automated, saving time and avoiding delays.</li><li><strong>Knowledge Base &amp; Self-Service Portal:</strong> Staff and volunteers can quickly find guides, FAQs, and best practices, helping them respond faster and more efficiently.</li><li><strong>Impact Analytics &amp; Reporting:</strong> Dashboards show real results, response times, security incidents prevented, and efficiency improvements, so nonprofits can see the real impact.</li></ul>
<p><strong>ServiceNow Products / Capabilities to use:</strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>IT Service Management (ITSM):</strong> For tracking cases, automating workflows, and resolving incidents.</li><li><strong>Security Operations (SecOps):</strong> To detect, prioritize, and respond to cybersecurity threats.</li><li><strong>Now Platform / App Engine:</strong> To build custom workflows, dashboards, and portals tailored to nonprofits.</li><li><strong>Knowledge Management &amp; Service Portal:</strong> So staff and volunteers can self-serve and find what they need quickly.</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics:</strong> To track results, visualize trends, and generate actionable insights.</li></ul>
<p>This solution blends security, efficiency, and transparency, giving nonprofits the freedom to focus on their mission while keeping their operations safe and optimized.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>To make this solution work smoothly, there are a few technical pieces we would rely on:</p>
<ul><li><strong>ServiceNow Platform Access:</strong> The hub needs the Now Platform to build custom workflows, dashboards, and portals.</li><li><strong>ITSM &amp; SecOps Modules:</strong> These are required for incident tracking, automation, and cybersecurity monitoring.</li><li><strong>Integration Capabilities:</strong> Some nonprofits might use external tools for donations, volunteer management, or email, so we would need APIs or connectors to pull data in seamlessly.</li><li><strong>User Authentication &amp; Permissions:</strong> Proper setup for staff and volunteers to securely access the portal and case management system.</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics Configuration:</strong> Dashboards and reports need the analytics module to measure impact and track trends.</li></ul>
<p>Basically, as long as the nonprofit has access to the ServiceNow modules and we can connect necessary external systems, the solution can run efficiently.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>A few things could make implementing this a bit tricky:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Access to ServiceNow Modules:</strong> Not all nonprofits may have the required ITSM or SecOps modules, which could limit functionality.</li><li><strong>Tech Familiarity:</strong> Some staff or volunteers might not be super comfortable with new software, so training and adoption could take time.</li><li><strong>Integration Complexity:</strong> Connecting external systems like donation platforms or volunteer management tools could require custom work.</li><li><strong>Resource Constraints:</strong> Nonprofits often operate with limited budgets or IT support, which might slow deployment or maintenance.</li><li><strong>Data Privacy &amp; Security:</strong> Handling sensitive donor, volunteer, or operational data securely will need careful setup and monitoring.</li></ul>
<p>Even with these challenges, I feel the solution is totally doable, and with smart planning, it could make a huge difference for nonprofits.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-21 22:32:20</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>1690396c83fcf610bfe895d6feaad3b8</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>SafeDonor: Nonprofit Digital Risk Guardian</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_1690396c83fcf610bfe895d6feaad3b8</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-21 22:32:22</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
