<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>no</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>There would be an improvement in the alignment of training offerings to job market demand by <strong>at least 30-50%</strong> in pilot regions. An increase in the employment rate of graduates by 25% and a reduced mismatch between graduates’ skills and employer requirements.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Many young Nigerians attend technical colleges or online courses, but they (and the training centers) often don’t know which skills are in demand locally (in Lagos, Abuja, or Port Harcourt) or abroad vs. what they are offering. There’s often a lag between job market demand and course content. Some skills become obsolete or saturated. Youth waste time/money studying things with poor employability.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>LearnAI Hub – Predictive Skill Gap Analyzer</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>LearnAI Hub would analyze data, predict trends, and guide decisions:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Predictive Intelligence ingests</strong> job vacancy data, skills keywords, and training course metadata to forecast which skills (e.g., data science, cloud, mobile dev, and cybersecurity) will be most in demand in the next 12-24 months in specific Nigerian cities or regions.</li><li><strong>App Engine Studio:</strong> Maintain a catalogue of training programs, learner profiles, course outcomes, and alignment scoring.</li><li><strong>IntegrationHub:</strong> Pull job listings from LinkedIn, Jobberman, and Indeed (or regional job boards); perhaps scrape or use APIs for skills tags.</li><li><strong>Flow Designer:</strong> Notify training providers or students when certain courses are likely to be in high demand; suggest tailored learning paths; send reminders.</li><li><strong>Service Portal:</strong> Allow individuals to see what skills are hot and what courses to take and companies to publish what skills they seek.</li><li><strong>Reporting &amp; Dashboards/Performance Analytics:</strong> Show which skills are rising/falling and where supply is lacking, and allow training institutions to adjust curriculum; learners decide better.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>Required:</strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>Job market intelligence API or scraper</strong> → pulls live or near-real-time demand data for skills, roles, industries, and hiring trends.</li><li><strong>Course/learning provider metadata API</strong> → structured data on course topics, format, outcomes, certifications offered, etc.</li></ul>
<p><strong>Optional (but highly valuable for long-term impact &amp; feedback loop intelligence):</strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>Certification provider API</strong> (e.g., Coursera, AWS, Cisco, Oracle) → match users to globally recognized cert prep paths.</li><li><strong>Employer feedback / placement outcome API</strong> → companies rate candidate readiness → model learns what training actually leads to hiring.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>Data quality &amp; bias:</strong> job listings may overrepresent certain sectors or geographies; scraping has issues; skill tags are inconsistent.</li><li><strong>Privacy &amp; ethics:</strong> individual learner data must be protected; predictions must not discourage learners.</li><li><strong>Adoption by training institutions:</strong> they must trust the recommendations to adapt the curriculum.</li><li><strong>Local relevance:</strong> ensure that predictions are tailored to local economies, not just global trends.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-21 09:54:54</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>60488b94c37c3210a77f7c2ed401310e</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>LearnAI Hub – Predictive Skill Gap Analyzer</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_60488b94c37c3210a77f7c2ed401310e</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-21 09:54:56</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
