<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Implementing AquaSentinel would bring a measurable transformation to how NGOs, governments, and communities manage water safety and sanitation:</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Faster Contamination Response:</strong><br />Automated alerts from IoT sensors integrated with ServiceNow workflows can detect contamination instantly, reducing response time from days or weeks to a few hours.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Reduction in Water-Borne Diseases:</strong><br />With proactive monitoring and faster intervention, communities could see a 40–60% decrease in water-borne illness outbreaks such as cholera or typhoid over time.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Improved Resource Allocation:</strong><br />Real-time analytics would allow organizations to prioritize high-risk zones, ensuring efficient deployment of water treatment and medical resources, potentially improving operational efficiency by up to 30%.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>DataDriven Decision Making</strong>:<br />Centralized dashboards would help NGOs and local governments track trends, identify root causes, and make informed policy decisions for long-term sanitation improvement.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Sustainability and Community Empowerment:</strong><br />Communities would gain awareness and ownership of their water safety through transparent data access and education programs  contributing directly to SDG 3 (Good Health), SDG 6 (Clean Water), and SDG 13 (Climate Action).</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">By creating a connected, proactive, and transparent ecosystem for water and sanitation monitoring, AquaSentinel would save lives, strengthen public health systems, and support sustainable environmental practices globally.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Access to clean and safe water remains one of the most pressing challenges in many developing regions. Contaminated water sources caused by industrial waste, poor sanitation, or natural disasters lead to widespread outbreaks of preventable diseases such as cholera, typhoid, and dysentery.&#13;
&#13;
Despite ongoing efforts by NGOs and local authorities, the problem persists because water-quality monitoring is often manual, reactive, and fragmented. Reports are collected through paper forms or periodic sampling, which delays detection of contamination. Many rural communities lack proper infrastructure or digital tools for consistent water testing and data reporting.&#13;
&#13;
During flood seasons or drought periods, contamination levels fluctuate rapidly, and without real-time visibility, response teams cannot act quickly to prevent health crises. Additionally, multiple organizations operate independently  health workers, NGOs, and environmental agencies without a unified data-sharing platform, leading to duplication of efforts and delayed interventions.&#13;
&#13;
There is an urgent need for a centralized, intelligent system that connects communities, NGOs, and public health authorities, offering real-time insights into water quality, sanitation risks, and environmental impact. Such a system would enable proactive response, optimize resource allocation, and ultimately reduce water-borne disease outbreaks.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>AquaSentinel – Smart Water Safety &amp; Sanitation Monitoring Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">The ideal solution is a centralized water-quality monitoring and response platform built on ServiceNow, integrating IoT, automation, and analytics to connect field sensors, health agencies, and NGOs in real time.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">IoT sensors are installed at key water points to continuously monitor metrics like pH, turbidity, temperature, and contaminant levels.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Data from these sensors flows into ServiceNow through IntegrationHub, where it’s automatically analyzed and visualized.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">If any reading crosses a danger threshold, Flow Designer triggers a workflow that creates a case in ServiceNow Case Management, notifies local health officers, and dispatches response teams immediately.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Performance Analytics dashboards provide trend insights, mapping contamination over time and predicting high-risk areas based on historical data and environmental conditions.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Service Portal allows NGOs, communities, and government agencies to view water safety reports, track ongoing cases, and collaborate seamlessly.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">A Virtual Agent can be embedded to allow community members to report issues via voice or chat in local languages, ensuring inclusivity and accessibility.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Key ServiceNow Products &amp; Capabilities:</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>IntegrationHub:</strong> for real time IoT and API data integration</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Flow Designer:</strong> for automated alert and case workflows</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Case Management</strong>: to handle contamination incidents efficiently</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Performance Analytics:</strong> for monitoring water-quality trends and KPIs</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Service Portal &amp; Virtual Agent:</strong> for stakeholder collaboration and public engagement</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">This end to end ServiceNow solution enables predictive water safety management, ensuring faster interventions, transparency, and long-term sustainability.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Yes  implementing AquaSentinel will rely on a combination of hardware, software, and data-integration technologies to ensure accurate, real-time water-quality monitoring and automated responses.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong> IoT Hardware &amp; Connectivity:</strong></p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Smart water-quality sensors capable of measuring pH, turbidity, dissolved oxygen, and contaminant levels.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Edge devices or gateways for transmitting sensor data to the cloud.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Reliable internet or GSM connectivity for continuous data transfer.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong> Cloud &amp; API Integrations:</strong></p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Secure APIs to connect IoT sensor platforms with ServiceNow IntegrationHub.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Environmental data APIs (e.g., rainfall, temperature, or pollution indices) for contextual insights.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Cloud database or storage for historical water-quality data archiving.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"> <strong>ServiceNow Platform Requirements:</strong></p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">IntegrationHub Spokes for IoT and mapping tools.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Performance Analytics and Flow Designer activated for automation and insights.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Service Portal for multi-stakeholder access (NGOs, agencies, communities).</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"><strong>Security &amp; Compliance:</strong></p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Data encryption protocols for transmitting sensitive environmental and community data.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt 0.5in; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;">Compliance with regional data protection standards (e.g., GDPR or national privacy acts).</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: 107%; font-size: 11pt; font-family: Aptos, sans-serif;"> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Limited Infrastructure in Remote Areas<br />Many rural or underserved regions may lack stable internet or power supply, making it difficult to collect and transmit real-time sensor data consistently.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Sensor Maintenance and Calibration<br />IoT water-quality sensors require regular calibration and maintenance to ensure accurate readings. This could be challenging in areas without local technical expertise.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Data Accuracy and Reliability<br />Variations in environmental conditions and sensor performance can lead to data inconsistencies. Ensuring high-quality, verified data for decision-making will require robust validation mechanisms.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Integration Complexity<br />Connecting multiple IoT devices, APIs, and data sources into the ServiceNow platform could present technical challenges  especially in synchronizing real-time updates across regions.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Cost and Scalability<br />Initial setup costs for hardware, connectivity, and training could be high, and scaling the solution across multiple communities or countries would require significant investment.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Data Privacy and Governance<br />Collecting and storing environmental and community data must comply with data protection laws. Establishing clear governance policies for who can access or share this data will be essential.</p>
</li><li>
<p>User Adoption and Capacity Building<br />Field officers, NGOs, and community members may need training to use the platform effectively. Building local digital literacy will be key to long-term success.</p>
</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-24 16:05:05</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>11818c25c3303210873e7cec05013167</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>AquaSentinel – Smart Water Safety &amp; Sanitation Monitoring Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_11818c25c3303210873e7cec05013167</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-24 16:05:07</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
