<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>The She-Trial Connect solution can bridge the gap in women’s health research by enabling faster, fairer access to clinical trials. Using ServiceNow’s AI Agents and Workflow Data Fabric, it can match eligible participants in minutes, empower NGOs and hospitals with real-time insights, and significantly increase women’s participation in global health studies. This improves health equity, accelerates medical discoveries, and builds community trust through secure, multilingual, and privacy-compliant digital engagement.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Women remain underrepresented in clinical trials due to limited awareness, complex eligibility criteria, and lack of accessible digital platforms. This gap slows progress in women’s health research and creates inequity in medical innovation and treatment outcomes. thats where She-trial Connect helps and fill the gaps.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>SheWomen Connect</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The She-Trial Connect solution can revolutionize women’s health participation by making clinical trials more accessible, inclusive, and transparent. Using ServiceNow’s AI Agents and Workflow Data Fabric, it can match eligible participants in minutes instead of months, increase female representation in research, and empower NGOs and hospitals with real-time dashboards.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Integrating multiple clinical-trial databases with different standards may pose data consistency challenges. Ensuring HIPAA/GDPR compliance, maintaining AI accuracy, and driving adoption among healthcare partners while supporting multilingual, inclusive access will require careful planning and collaboration.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Implementing She-Trial Connect may face challenges such as integrating diverse clinical-trial data sources and ensuring compliance with HIPAA and GDPR standards. Maintaining AI accuracy and fairness, driving adoption among hospitals and NGOs, and supporting multilingual, accessible user experiences will also require careful design, data governance, and ongoing collaboration with healthcare partners.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-11 23:46:00</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>8c82f69d832872106705c710feaad346</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>SheWomen Connect</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_8c82f69d832872106705c710feaad346</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-11 23:46:01</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
