<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A platform that connects users with nearby restaurants for recurring meal plans can:</p>
<ul><li>Provide time-saving, affordable meal options for busy individuals.</li><li>Generate consistent revenue for local restaurants.</li><li>Enable restaurants to optimize inventory and reduce food waste.</li><li>Improve customer satisfaction through personalized meal offerings.</li></ul>
<p><strong>Measurable outcomes:</strong></p>
<ul><li>1,000&#43; recurring meal subscriptions in the first 6 months.</li><li>20% reduction in food waste through better inventory planning.</li><li>Increased restaurant revenue and customer retention.</li><li>Improved health and convenience for urban professionals.</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>In fast-paced urban environments, working professionals often struggle to find time to cook or plan meals. Meanwhile, local restaurants face challenges in maintaining consistent revenue and managing inventory efficiently. There’s a gap between consumers who need reliable, healthy meals and restaurants that need recurring customers and data-driven insights to optimize operations.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>MealLink – Smart Meal Subscription &amp; Restaurant Optimization Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>Service Portal</strong> – for user and restaurant registration, meal browsing, and subscription management</li><li><strong>Record Producer</strong> – to collect user and restaurant details</li><li><strong>Flow Designer</strong> – to automate grouping, subscription workflows, and notifications</li><li><strong>Virtual Agent</strong> – for meal plan guidance, FAQs, and support</li><li><strong>Notification Engine</strong> – to send meal reminders, offers, and updates</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics</strong> – to track user preferences, restaurant performance, and inventory trends</li><li><strong>IntegrationHub</strong> – for connecting with delivery services, payment gateways, and distributor systems</li><li><strong>Survey Management</strong> – for collecting feedback on meals and service quality</li><li><strong>Now Mobile (optional)</strong> – for mobile access to meal plans and notifications</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Integration with payment gateways for subscription billing</li><li>Integration with delivery services for meal logistics</li><li>Secure handling of user data and preferences</li><li>Dynamic grouping logic based on pincode</li><li>Optional integration with restaurant POS or inventory systems</li><li>Mobile accessibility for users and restaurant staff</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Ensuring accurate and timely meal delivery coordination</li><li>Managing subscription changes and cancellations</li><li>Handling diverse food preferences and dietary restrictions</li><li>Encouraging restaurant participation and data sharing</li><li>Scaling the platform across multiple cities and regions</li><li>Maintaining data privacy and secure transactions</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-24 12:40:44</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>e7e653558338b2102bb16f60ceaad3cb</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>MealLink – Smart Meal Subscription &amp; Restaurant Optimization Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_e7e653558338b2102bb16f60ceaad3cb</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-24 12:40:46</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
