<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li><strong>AI-powered local insights:</strong> EcoMind collects and analyzes data from IoT sensors, public datasets, and citizen reports to detect micro-climate patterns (e.g., heat zones, water wastage, tree cover loss).</li><li><strong>Predictive action dashboard: </strong>Provides local authorities and NGOs with early alerts (e.g., “Air quality expected to cross safe limits tomorrow”) for preventive action.</li><li><strong>Citizen engagement:</strong> Residents can report eco-issues (waste, air pollution, green cover loss) through an intuitive interface and receive AI-generated local eco-scores.</li><li><strong>Global vision: </strong>Aggregated data can contribute to national and UN climate tracking efforts, empowering smarter, community-led climate resilience.</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Communities around the world face localized environmental challenges — rising temperatures, urban heat islands, poor air quality, and inconsistent waste or water management.&#13;
However, climate action data is fragmented and local governments often lack real-time insights to respond effectively.&#13;
Citizens see environmental changes daily, but there’s no smart system that connects their observations with actionable insights or city responses.&#13;
There is a clear gap between awareness and coordinated, data-driven climate action.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>CitiGreen – empowering smart, green city decisions.</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>ServiceNow Impact / ESG Management:</strong> For tracking environmental KPIs and sustainability goals.</li><li><strong>Now Platform App Engine: </strong>To build the citizen portal, report workflows, and AI-driven dashboards.</li><li><strong>ServiceNow Predictive Intelligence:</strong> To classify and prioritize environmental reports using machine learning.</li><li><strong>ServiceNow Flow Designer:</strong> To automate responses and route alerts to relevant local departments or NGOs.</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics</strong>: To visualize trends (air, water, waste metrics) and assess impact over time.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>Data Feeds:</strong> Access to IoT sensor data (air quality, temperature, water levels), satellite data, or open municipal datasets.</li><li><strong>AI Model Integration: </strong>Use of AI APIs (like Azure ML, TensorFlow, or Hugging Face models) for anomaly detection and prediction.</li><li><strong>Mobile &amp; Web Interfaces:</strong> Integration of ServiceNow workflows with a responsive citizen-facing app (React / Flutter).</li><li><strong>Secure Cloud Hosting: </strong>ServiceNow cloud or partner integrations for scalable data handling.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>Data availability:</strong> Real-time environmental data collection can be inconsistent or limited by region.</li><li><strong>Integration complexity: </strong>Merging ServiceNow workflows with external IoT and AI systems may need careful API management.</li><li><strong>Public engagement: </strong>Sustaining citizen participation and data accuracy requires strong UX and incentive design.</li><li><strong>AI bias &amp; validation:</strong> Ensuring AI models make fair and contextually correct recommendations for different localities.</li><li><strong>Scalability: </strong>Handling data from multiple cities or regions efficiently within ServiceNow workflows.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-23 13:30:44</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>64271a0d833032107980a6d0deaad3fd</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>CitiGreen – empowering smart, green city decisions.</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_64271a0d833032107980a6d0deaad3fd</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-23 13:30:46</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
