<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A technology solution like CareConnect would have a transformative impact on both NGO workers and the organizations themselves, creating a healthier, more sustainable social sector.</p>
<p>Measurable Impact:</p>
<p><strong>For NGOs:</strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>Increase in Staff Retention: </strong>Reduce costly turnover by providing concrete support, directly retaining institutional knowledge and experience.</li><li><strong>Reduction in Burnout-Related Absenteeism:</strong> Improve overall team capacity and productivity by addressing a key cause of sick leave.</li><li><strong>Improved Organizational Resilience: </strong>Build a more robust workforce that can better handle chronic stress and crisis situations.</li></ul>
<p><strong>For NGO Workers:</strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>Increased Help-Seeking Behavior:</strong> By reducing stigma and friction, more employees would utilize available mental health resources.</li><li><strong>Measurable Improvement in Well-being:</strong> Use anonymized survey data to track improvements in staff morale, job satisfaction, and mental wellness scores.</li><li><strong>Faster Access to Support:</strong> Drastically reduce the time between recognizing distress and connecting with a helpful resource.</li></ul>
<p>In short, the solution protects the protectors. By safeguarding the mental health of NGO workers, we ensure they can continue their vital missions effectively and sustainably for the long term.</p>
<p> </p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Nonprofit workers are on the front lines of society's toughest challenges, constantly exposed to trauma, high stress, and resource constraints. This leads to widespread burnout, compassion fatigue, and mental health strain.&#13;
&#13;
However, seeking help is often stigmatized, and NGOs focused on their external mission, frequently lack the structured support and accessible, confidential channels to protect the well-being of their most valuable asset: their people. This silent crisis threatens staff retention, operational effectiveness, and the long-term health of the entire social sector.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>CareConnect – Mental Health Access for NGO Workers</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p style="margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">The ideal solution is a confidential, centralized hub on the ServiceNow platform that makes seeking help a normalized, low-friction, and private experience for every NGO employee.</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Here’s how specific ServiceNow capabilities would power this:</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">1. Employee Service Center &amp; HR Service Delivery: </span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">This would form the core interface. It would provide a single, familiar place for employees to:</span></p>
<ul><li><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Access a Service Catalog to easily request a counseling session or a wellness check-in.</span></li><li>Find a Knowledge Base of self-help articles, stress-management guides, and mental health resources.</li></ul>
<p style="margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">2. Case and Incident Management: </span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Each request for support would automatically create a confidential HR case. This allows for:</span></p>
<ul><li><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Structured Workflow: The case can be securely routed to the appropriate internal well-being champion or an external, integrated partner.</span></li><li>Privacy Assurance: Sensitive information is kept within a controlled, secure system with appropriate access controls.</li></ul>
<p style="margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">3. Integration Hub:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;"> This is key for creating a seamless ecosystem. The solution would connect with:</span></p>
<ul><li><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Scheduling tools (like Calendly) to book sessions directly.</span></li><li>External teletherapy or EAP (Employee Assistance Program) providers to pull in available resources and session credits.</li></ul>
<p style="margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">4. Performance Analytics: </span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">To measure impact while preserving anonymity, we would build leadership dashboards that show:</span></p>
<ul><li><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Aggregate usage trends</span></li><li><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Anonymous well-being survey scores over time.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: 11pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Overall reduction in burnout-related HR cases.</span></li></ul>
<p style="margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">In essence, we use ServiceNow not just as a workflow tool, but as a platform to build a culture of care, making well-being a seamless and supported part of an NGO&#39;s operations.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: Roboto, sans-serif; color: rgb(15, 17, 21);">The solution is designed to be built on the core ServiceNow Platform, minimizing external dependencies for the initial prototype. The key dependencies are:</span></p>
<ol style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px; padding-inline-start: 48px;"><li style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: Roboto, sans-serif; color: rgb(15, 17, 21); text-wrap-mode: nowrap;">
<p style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 12pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">ServiceNow Platform Access:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 12pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;"> The primary requirement is a Developer Instance with access to HR Service Delivery and Employee Service Center to build the confidential hub, service catalog, and case management workflows.</span></p>
</li><li style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: Roboto, sans-serif; color: rgb(15, 17, 21); text-wrap-mode: nowrap;">
<p style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 12pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Integration with External Providers (for a live solution):</span></strong><span style="font-size: 12pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;"> To provide real counseling sessions, the solution would eventually need secure integrations with external teletherapy platforms or Employee Assistance Programs (EAPs) via ServiceNow IntegrationHub.</span></p>
</li><li style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: Roboto, sans-serif; color: rgb(15, 17, 21); text-wrap-mode: nowrap;">
<p style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 12pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;">Organizational Buy-in and Process:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 12pt; text-wrap-mode: wrap;"> A non-technical but critical dependency is the NGO&#39;s commitment to establishing a supportive well-being policy and securing the internal or external specialists to fulfill the support requests.</span></p>
</li></ol>
<p style="margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: Roboto, sans-serif; color: rgb(15, 17, 21); background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);">This means we can start providing support to NGO workers right away, and easily expand the help we offer over time.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>The main challenges would be:</p>
<ol start="1"><li>
<p><strong>Cultural Stigma:</strong> The biggest hurdle is encouraging people to use the platform in environments where discussing mental health is often taboo. Success depends on building absolute trust in its confidentiality.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Resource Availability:</strong> The platform can connect employees to help, but it relies on the NGO having partnerships with counselors or the budget to provide these services, which can be a constraint.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Driving Consistent Engagement:</strong> It&#39;s a challenge to make the platform a natural and ongoing part of an employee&#39;s routine, rather than a one-time resource they forget about.</p>
</li></ol>
<p>We would address these by designing with privacy at the forefront, providing guidance on low-cost support resources, and using the platform to promote a culture of wellness from leadership down.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-23 20:42:16</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>645773c1833c3e10bfe895d6feaad3ad</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>CareConnect – Mental Health Access for NGO Workers</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_645773c1833c3e10bfe895d6feaad3ad</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-23 20:42:17</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
