<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Encourages <strong>continuous learning</strong> without formal courses.<br />Helps users <strong>develop both technical and soft skills</strong> through teaching and collaboration.<br />Creates opportunities for knowledge-sharing across industries and expertise levels.<strong><br /></strong>Fosters meaningful professional connections and mentorship.<br />Encourages collaboration, communication, and mutual accountability.<br />Builds confidence in both teaching and learning roles.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Many professionals and learners want to acquire new skills, but formal courses can be expensive or time-consuming. Often, someone with real time expertise in one area wants to learn another skill, while another person wants the reverse.&#13;
Currently, there’s no structured platform for pairing learners with complementary skills to teach each other efficiently. Without guidance, it’s hard to find the right partner, track progress, and maintain accountability.&#13;
for example, I want to learn Salesforce and Someone wants to learn ServiceNow, we can use this and share our knowledge and skills with each other</problem_statement>
        <project_name>SkillBuddy: A ServiceNow App for Mutual Learning and Mentorship</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>ServiceNow App Engine</strong> – Core skill pairing, session scheduling, and workflow management.<br /><strong>UI Builder / Service Portal</strong> – User-friendly dashboard for learning, teaching, and tracking.<br /><strong>Flow Designer</strong> – Automate reminders, notifications, and milestone tracking.<br /><strong>IntegrationHub</strong> – Optional video call, chat, or resource-sharing integration.<br /><strong>Reporting &amp; Analytics</strong> – Track skill exchanges, user engagement, and learning outcomes.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>None all using, we can develop everything using out of the box capabilities </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>None; Language barriers may exist but we will encourage users to use their mother tongue or language comfortable to them </p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-27 19:39:26</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>00b2dc66c3b832105b91be3ed4013134</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>SkillBuddy: A ServiceNow App for Mutual Learning and Mentorship</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_00b2dc66c3b832105b91be3ed4013134</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-27 19:39:27</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
