<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A ServiceNow-based telemedicine platform would connect rural patients with doctors and specialists through video consultations, eliminating travel barriers. The platform would manage appointment scheduling, patient records, prescription delivery, and follow-up care. It could integrate with India&#39;s eSanjeevani initiative (which has served 340 million patients) and leverage the network of 176,534 Health and Wellness Centers across rural India.</p>
<p>This would reduce healthcare costs by 50%, improve access for women and elderly populations, enable early diagnosis of chronic conditions, and save lives through timely medical intervention. The platform could serve millions in underserved areas while reducing the burden on urban hospitals. </p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>India faces a major healthcare gap with 70% of healthcare infrastructure concentrated in urban areas serving only 30% of the population. Rural areas have a doctor-to-patient ratio of 1:2500, much worse than the WHO recommendation of 1:1000. Over 86% of medical visits by rural residents involve journeys exceeding 100 km, creating huge barriers to healthcare access. Women and elderly populations in rural areas often avoid seeking medical care due to distance, cost, and lack of transportation.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Rural Health Connect</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The platform would include a patient portal (mobile and web) where rural residents can book appointments, upload symptoms and photos, and connect with doctors via video calls.</p>
<p>A doctor dashboard would manage appointments, view patient history, write digital prescriptions, and refer to specialists when needed.</p>
<p>The system would have offline capability for areas with poor connectivity, automatic language translation for regional languages, and integration with pharmacy networks for medicine delivery.</p>
<p>Health workers at rural centers would assist patients in using the platform and collect basic vitals before consultations. </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>ServiceNow App Engine Studio for rapid application development</li><li>Integration with video conferencing platforms (Zoom, Teams) via APIs</li><li>Mobile app development for Android (majority of rural users)</li><li>Offline data sync capability using ServiceNow Mobile Agent</li><li>Integration Hub for connecting with pharmacy and payment systems</li><li>WhatsApp integration for appointment reminders and notifications (widely used in rural India)</li><li>Multi-language support for Hindi, Tamil, Telugu, Bengali, and other regional languages</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Ensuring reliable internet connectivity and power in remote areas, training health workers on digital tools, and integrating with varied local healthcare systems would probably be the major challenges in implementing this idea.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-19 09:51:23</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>369d7cf747247210ca05a464116d437e</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Rural Health Connect</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_369d7cf747247210ca05a464116d437e</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-19 09:51:26</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
