<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A ServiceNow-driven intelligent application can:</p>
<p>Enable real-time pangolin conservation incident tracking and response<br />Digitally connect conservation field teams, governments, and NGOs in one shared, trusted platform<br />Integrate telemetry, camera trap, and ranger patrol data into actionable conservation workflows<br />Provide predictive insights into poaching risks and habitat threats<br />Digitize evidence collection and chain of custody for rescued pangolins or seized goods<br />Offer data transparency for international wildlife trade monitoring (CITES compliance)<br />Support sustainable local stewardship with mobile tools for indigenous communities</p>
<p>This would shift conservation from reactive &amp; siloed to proactive &amp; integrated, powered by automation, data intelligence, and actionable workflows</p>
<p> </p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Pangolins are the most trafficked mammals in the world, despite being vital to ecosystems as insectivores that naturally control termite and ant populations. Conservation efforts are severely hampered by:&#13;
&#13;
Lack of real-time data on pangolin movements and habitats&#13;
&#13;
Disconnected monitoring systems between conservationists, rangers, NGOs, and government agencies&#13;
&#13;
Manual, delayed, or reactive interventions instead of predictive and proactive responses&#13;
&#13;
Inefficient coordination for habitat protection, poaching incident response, and rescue operations&#13;
&#13;
Lack of transparency and audit trails for anti-poaching actions and wildlife trade tracking&#13;
&#13;
Despite advances in ecology and environmental biology, the systems used to protect pangolins are fragmented, outdated, and underfunded, with no single digital workflow hub to orchestrate detection, intervention, and follow-up</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Pangolink — A Real-Time Anti-Poaching &amp; Conservation Intelligence Network for Pangolins</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><h4><strong>Pangolink is a  centralized ServiceNow platform that tracks and manages real-time pangolin movement, poaching incidents, rescue operations, and habitat integrity across ecosystems.</strong></h4>
<p>Key Modules &amp; Features</p>
<h3><strong>1. Pangolin Incident Intelligence Dashboard</strong></h3>
<p>Real-time dashboard of all reported sightings, poaching events, habitat alerts</p>
<p>Visual map with geofencing for protected areas, patrol routes, sensor zones</p>
<p>Heatmaps of high-risk areas and historical trends</p>
<h3><strong>2. Conservation Incident Lifecycle Management</strong></h3>
<p>Auto-creation of &#34;Conservation Incident&#34; records for:</p>
<p>Poaching alerts (e.g., gunshots detected by acoustic sensors)</p>
<p>Illegal trade shipments</p>
<p>Snares or traps found</p>
<p>Injured pangolins reported</p>
<p>Workflows assign follow-up tasks (inspection, veterinary care, transfer to rehab)</p>
<h3><strong>3. Telemetry &amp; Sensor Integration</strong></h3>
<p>Integrate GPS-tagged pangolin collars for movement data</p>
<p>Ingest acoustic gunshot sensors, camera trap images, or drone data</p>
<p>Anomaly detection alerts for irregular pangolin movement or inactivity</p>
<h3><strong>4. Field Team Coordination (Mobile)</strong></h3>
<p>Assign rangers or wildlife officers tasks from incidents</p>
<p>Capture photos, GPS, and field notes</p>
<p>Barcode tagging of confiscated pangolins or goods (for evidence tracking)</p>
<h3><strong>5. Chain of Custody &amp; Legal Evidence Management</strong></h3>
<p>Track seized pangolins or goods from capture to rehab or legal outcome</p>
<p>Secure uploads of documents, images, and forensic reports</p>
<p>Supports CITES reporting and national legal frameworks</p>
<h3><strong>6. Community Reporting Portal</strong></h3>
<p>Mobile/web-based reporting for local communities</p>
<p>Anonymous tip lines for poaching or suspicious activity</p>
<p>Gamified education portal on pangolin importance and local ecosystem benefits</p>
<h3><strong>7. Predictive Risk Engine</strong></h3>
<p>Use historical data &#43; environmental changes to score regions for future poaching risk</p>
<p>Seasonal modeling for increased ranger presence (based on demand forecasting)</p>
<h3><strong>8. Partnership &amp; NGO Dashboard</strong></h3>
<p>Allow NGOs and international partners to view anonymized, role-based data</p>
<p>Upload and track grant-funded conservation efforts and outcomes</p>
<p><strong>Capabilities</strong></p>
<p><strong>ServiceNow Platform (Core):</strong> Used for defining the data model, managing record lifecycles, and setting up notifications.</p>
<p><strong>Field Service Management (FSM):</strong> Helps assign ranger patrols and veterinary tasks in the field.</p>
<p><strong>Flow Designer / IntegrationHub:</strong> Automates workflows, such as triggering incidents from sensor input.</p>
<p><strong>Service Portal &amp; Mobile App Builder:</strong> Enables features like a community tipline and allows field teams to enter data directly.</p>
<p><strong>Performance Analytics &amp; Dashboards:</strong> Tracks conservation KPIs, trends, and sends alerts based on performance data.</p>
<p><strong>Predictive Intelligence:</strong> Applies risk scoring to identify potential poaching or habitat degradation.</p>
<p><strong>Security &amp; ACLs:</strong> Enforces role-based access control for different user groups like government agencies, NGOs, and rangers.</p>
<p><strong>Document Management:</strong> Used to store critical files like permits, reports, and evidence.</p>
<p><strong>Geolocation &amp; Maps:</strong> Visualizes pangolin movements, sensor coverage areas, and reported poaching incidents.</p>
<p><strong>Now Assist (GenAI):</strong> Assists in summarizing incidents, auto-generating reports, and classifying threats from textual data.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Open datasets of pangolin telemetry (or simulated data)</p>
<p>Integration connectors (REST/API) to:</p>
<p>Smart collar GPS systems (e.g., LoRaWAN or satellite)</p>
<p>Sensor platforms (acoustic gunshot, camera traps)</p>
<p>Drone or satellite imagery providers (optional)</p>
<p>AI models for:</p>
<p>Classifying camera trap images</p>
<p>Predictive poaching risk scoring</p>
<p>Open-source map layer (e.g., Leaflet or Mapbox integration in portal)</p>
<p>Secure, permissioned storage of sensitive data (e.g., wildlife locations, legal cases)</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>1. Data Sensitivity &amp; Security</strong></p>
<p>Pangolin location data must be protected from misuse (e.g., used by traffickers)</p>
<p>Legal evidence must be immutable and secure</p>
<p><strong>2. Interagency Coordination</strong></p>
<p>Requires buy-in from government wildlife agencies, NGOs, and law enforcement</p>
<p><strong>3. Connectivity in Field Locations</strong></p>
<p>Many habitats have no signal; offline mobile access and syncing needed</p>
<p><strong>4. Data Quality &amp; Standardization</strong></p>
<p>Diverse sensor types, data formats; need data cleansing and normalization</p>
<p><strong>5. Ethical AI Use</strong></p>
<p>Avoid false positives in poaching predictions that might unfairly target communities</p>
<p><strong>6. Sustainability &amp; Funding</strong></p>
<p>Ongoing maintenance and operations need long-term funding partners</p>
<p><br /><br /><br /></p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-22 06:14:28</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>9ee9632c833832106e90c070ceaad391</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Pangolink — A Real-Time Anti-Poaching &amp; Conservation Intelligence Network for Pangolins</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_9ee9632c833832106e90c070ceaad391</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-22 06:14:29</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
