<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>no</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>By helping people choose the greenest possible route, balancing travel time, CO₂ emissions, and crowd data, GreenRoutes could reduce daily urban carbon output by measurable percentages and encourage public transport use.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Urban commuters often default to private cars due to inefficient public transport routes or lack of visibility into eco-friendly alternatives. This leads to congestion and high carbon emissions.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>GreenRoutes – AI-Driven Public Transport &amp; Walking Optimizer</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The following applications will be used to power our solution;</p>
<ul><li>ServiceNow App Engine for route suggestion workflows</li><li>IntegrationHub Spokes to connect to live transport APIs (e.g., Google Transit, City Bus, Train networks)<br /><br /></li><li>Now Experience UI for an interactive commuter dashboard</li><li>Flow Designer &#43; Predictive Intelligence to analyze historic route data and recommend greener options</li><li>Performance Analytics to show personal and community carbon savings over time</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>We would be Integrating APIs for public transit data and city mobility datasets (open data APIs) also Map rendering or GIS plugin </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Access to accurate real-time data from multiple transport providers and Encouraging adoption and behavioral change among commuters, also network connections are spotty.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-14 20:25:16</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>28edd11ac3e47610123cb132b4013158</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>GreenRoutes – AI-Driven Public Transport &amp; Walking Optimizer</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_28edd11ac3e47610123cb132b4013158</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-14 20:25:18</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
