<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>GreenTechNow is a ServiceNow-powered digital collaboration and innovation management platform designed to accelerate climate technology projects across industries and governments.</p>
<p>It connects innovators, regulators, investors, and auditors in one ecosystem — promoting transparent evaluation, funding, and monitoring of sustainability-focused innovations.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>One of the G20’s major goals is driving sustainable and green innovation through digital technology.&#13;
However, many startups, innovators, and research teams working on climate and green technology solutions face these key challenges:&#13;
&#13;
Fragmented collaboration channels between government, investors, and innovators.&#13;
&#13;
Slow approval and funding processes for green projects.&#13;
&#13;
Lack of centralized visibility into environmental impact metrics.&#13;
&#13;
As a result, great innovations in renewable energy, waste reduction, and carbon management struggle to move from idea to large-scale implementation.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>GreenTechNow – Accelerating Climate Tech Innovation through Digital Collaboration</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>App Engine Studio</p>
<p>Build a digital Innovation Portal where startups and institutions can submit green-tech proposals, upload prototypes, and request support.</p>
<p>Flow Designer &amp; Service Catalog</p>
<p>Automate proposal review and funding approval workflows involving multiple stakeholders (e.g., energy ministry, sustainability boards, or investors).</p>
<p>IntegrationHub</p>
<p>Connects with third-party carbon tracking systems, IoT platforms, or renewable energy data APIs to collect impact metrics (e.g., CO₂ reduction, energy efficiency rates).</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Integration with environmental data sources (IoT sensors, APIs, ESG databases).</p>
<p>Cloud-hosted ServiceNow instance with App Engine, IntegrationHub, GRC, and Performance Analytics.</p>
<p>API access for research institutions and environmental agencies.</p>
<p>Data encryption, role-based access control, and secure collaboration protocols.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Data standardization across global sustainability platforms.</p>
<p>Varying regulatory frameworks in G20 member countries.</p>
<p>Ensuring cybersecurity in cross-border data exchange.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-16 15:06:07</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>3bb76eb2c368721008fcbefdd401312c</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>GreenTechNow – Accelerating Climate Tech Innovation through Digital Collaboration</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_3bb76eb2c368721008fcbefdd401312c</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-16 15:06:09</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
