<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>ServiceNow University - A centralized platform helps rural youth access digital courses, career resources, and certification programs from anywhere. <br /><br />App Engine Studio - To design an intuitive and accessible user interface for learners, mentors, and administrators.<br /><br />Flow Designer - To automate workflows like user registration, course enrolment, progress updates, and feedback collection. <br /><br />UI Policies - To ensure dynamic form behaviour — for example, displaying (show/hide) mentor fields only when the user type is “Student&#34;.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Youth in remote villages face limited access to quality education, digital resources, and career guidance. Poor connectivity and lack of mentorship prevent them from upskilling or exploring career opportunities, widening the gap between rural and urban employment prospects.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>RemoteVRise: Bridging Skills and Career Opportunities for Village Youth</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>ServiceNow University, App Engine Studio, Flow Designer (Workflow Studio) and UI Policies.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p>No technical dependencies highlighted for this solution</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p>No particular challenges highlighted for this solution</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-27 17:48:36</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>b0193f5e83bc3210b3b7b5b6feaad3c5</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>RemoteVRise: Bridging Skills and Career Opportunities for Village Youth</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_b0193f5e83bc3210b3b7b5b6feaad3c5</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-27 17:48:40</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
