<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Potential impact:</p>
<p>Reduced recycling contamination through better public awareness and guided disposal.<br />Smarter, data-driven waste management for councils using live dashboards and analytics.<br />Increased recycling and e-waste recovery rates, contributing to Australia’s environmental goals.<br />Operational efficiency for waste collection teams through route optimization and mobile task tracking.<br />Empowered citizens who actively participate in sustainability through reports, education, and rewards.<br />Scalable national model that can expand across councils, schools, and community centers, promoting a culture of shared responsibility and environmental stewardship.</p>
<p>By connecting citizens, councils, and operators through ServiceNow, this solution transforms waste segregation into a smart, transparent, and collaborative ecosystem — helping Australia move closer to its Net Zero Waste vision.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Australian councils face growing challenges in ensuring correct waste segregation among residents.&#13;
Despite having clear bin systems (general waste, recycling, and green waste), many households remain unsure which bin to use for specific items. This leads to high contamination rates, recyclables being sent to landfill, and increased waste management costs.&#13;
&#13;
Additionally, dumper truck operators and waste collection teams often lack real-time visibility of community reports such as overflowing bins, illegal dumping, or missed pickups. There is no single system that connects residents, councils, and operators to work together efficiently.&#13;
&#13;
E-waste and bulky waste (like old TVs, cardboard moving boxes, or furniture) also pose significant issues — most residents are unaware of correct disposal points, leading to improper disposal and environmental harm.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Smart Waste Segregation &amp; Sustainability Portal</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>Value Proposition</strong></p>
<p>The Smart Waste Segregation &amp; Disposal Assistant creates a unified digital ecosystem that bridges the gap between citizens, councils, and waste operators.<br />By turning everyday waste disposal into a guided, data-driven, and collaborative experience, it promotes environmental responsibility and reduces contamination at the source.</p>
<p>Through automation, geolocation, and AI assistance, councils can optimize routes, track community issues in real time, and design targeted education programs. Residents gain convenience and clarity, while operators gain efficiency and transparency — resulting in a cleaner, greener, and smarter waste management system for Australia.</p>
<p><strong>Vision</strong></p>
<ul><li>Guided disposal instructions and public awareness campaigns lead to cleaner recycling streams and lower landfill contributions and contamination.</li><li>Real-time dashboards and analytics help councils identify problem areas, optimize collection schedules, and plan sustainability initiatives.</li><li>Residents can locate approved drop-off points for e-waste, bulky items, and cardboard, increasing proper disposal and resource recovery.</li><li>Route optimization, mobile task tracking, and automated dispatch reduce fuel usage, delays, and manual reporting for operational efficiency.</li><li>Community engagement through gamified reports, rewards, and education tools encourage citizens to actively participate in local sustainability efforts.</li><li>The platform can be scaled for adoption by councils, schools, and communities nationwide, fostering a culture of shared responsibility and environmental stewardship.</li></ul>
<p>By connecting citizens, councils, and waste operators through ServiceNow, this solution transforms waste segregation into a smart, transparent, and collaborative ecosystem, helping Australia move closer to its Net Zero Waste vision.</p>
<p><strong>ServiceNow Products and Capabilities Used</strong></p>
<ol><li>Service Portal / UI Builder: Resident self-service portal for waste lookup, pickups, and reporting.</li><li>Flow Designer: Automates workflows, notifications, and route assignments.</li><li>Virtual Agent / Now Assist: AI-powered chatbot that helps users determine correct bins or disposal centers.</li><li>App Engine Studio: Custom tables for Waste Items, Reports, Bins, Locations, and Operators.</li><li>Field Service Management (FSM): Assigns and tracks tasks for dumper truck operators.</li><li>Performance Analytics: Visualizes contamination rates, reports, and operational efficiency.</li><li>ActionPack: Custom automation components like ClassifyWasteItem, ReportWasteIssue, and SendWasteAlert.</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Integration with council waste APIs for bin schedules and regional recycling rules.</li><li>Integration with Google Maps or Geolocation APIs for locating nearby e-waste and bulk waste centers.</li><li>Integration with SMS/Email gateways (e.g., Twilio, SendGrid) for citizen notifications.</li><li>Optional AI/ML image recognition API for classifying uploaded waste item photos.</li><li>IoT integration for smart bins (fill-level sensors or GPS-enabled trucks) as a future enhancement.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Regional differences: Waste segregation rules and bin colors vary across councils (like disposal of soft plastics). I am not entirely sure of this. It is from a conversation I had a few months ago with someone living in a distant suburb.</li><li>Data accuracy: Ensuring reliable AI predictions and correct classification of waste types.</li><li>User adoption: Encouraging residents to use the digital platform instead of traditional methods (calls or emails).</li><li>Integration complexity: Connecting with multiple council APIs and external services (maps, waste centers).</li><li>Change management: Training operators and council staff to transition to the new system.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-05 23:53:49</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>de1aff1783d8fa107ffb1630ceaad367</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Smart Waste Segregation &amp; Sustainability Portal</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_de1aff1783d8fa107ffb1630ceaad367</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-05 23:53:50</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
