<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A ServiceNow-based climate refugee resettlement platform would provide dignified, coordinated relocation assistance for climate-displaced populations, match refugees with suitable host communities based on skills, language, and resources, accelerate integration through job placement and language training connections, coordinate services across NGOs, governments, and community organizations, track family reunification efforts, and provide data for long-term climate migration planning and resource allocation. </p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Climate change is displacing millions of people through rising sea levels, extreme weather events, droughts, and environmental disasters. By 2050, an estimated 200 million climate refugees will need relocation assistance. Current refugee resettlement systems are overwhelmed and not designed for climate-driven mass migration. &#13;
&#13;
Climate refugees face challenges including lack of legal status in many countries, difficulty finding housing and employment in new locations, language and cultural barriers, trauma and mental health needs, and family separation. Host communities struggle with rapid population influx, resource strain, and integration challenges. &#13;
&#13;
There is no coordinated global platform for managing climate-driven migration with dignity and efficiency.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>SafeHarbor Resettlement - Climate Refugee Settlement Coordinator</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The platform would feature: </p>
<p>1. Refugee Portal - multi-language interface for registration, document upload, family tracing, resettlement status tracking, and service requests.</p>
<p>2. Matching Engine - uses AI to match refugees with host communities based on employment opportunities, language, family connections, and community capacity.</p>
<p>3. Service Coordination Hub - connects refugees with housing, healthcare, education, job training, and legal assistance across multiple organizations.</p>
<p>4. Community Capacity Dashboard - shows host communities their current population, resource availability, and integration support needs.</p>
<p>5. Case Management - tracks individual refugee journeys from displacement through successful integration with milestone tracking. Integration with employment databases, housing registries, language training programs, and trauma counseling services would provide comprehensive support. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>ServiceNow Products/Capabilities used:</p>
<p>App Engine Studio, Customer Service Management, Case Management, Integration Hub, Virtual Agent with multi-language support, Mobile App Builder, Knowledge Management for refugee resources, Performance Analytics for resettlement outcomes</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>ServiceNow Customer Service Management for case tracking</li><li>Integration Hub for UN refugee databases (UNHCR), employment systems, housing registries, and identity verification</li><li>Multi-language support (20&#43; languages) with real-time translation</li><li>Mobile-first design for refugees with limited device access</li><li>Offline capability for areas with poor connectivity</li><li>Document management with secure storage for identity papers</li><li>Geolocation services for family tracing and service mapping</li><li>Virtual Agent for 24/7 information access in multiple languages</li><li>SMS/WhatsApp integration for low-tech communication</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Coordinating across multiple countries with different policies and systems, ensuring data security for vulnerable populations, addressing political sensitivities around migration, and scaling to handle potential mass displacement events would probably be the challenges in implementing this idea.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-20 04:05:13</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>9889f0c0933476104a52385efaba10a6</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>SafeHarbor Resettlement - Climate Refugee Settlement Coordinator</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_9889f0c0933476104a52385efaba10a6</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-20 04:05:14</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
