<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A digital community platform like <em>CleanConnect</em> would empower citizens to report and track local waste issues through a simple mobile or web interface.<br />Authorities can visualize these reports, assign cleanup tasks, and communicate updates to the public - creating accountability and engagement.</p>
<p><strong>Potential impacts include:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Reduction in illegal waste dumping and faster clean-up cycles.</li><li>Improved public hygiene and reduced disease risk.</li><li>Data-driven decision-making for waste management authorities.</li><li>Strengthened trust between citizens and local governments.</li><li>Scalable model that can be adapted for any country or city.</li><li>And overall a better planet for us. </li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>In India and many developing countries, cities struggle with poor waste management — overflowing bins, illegal dumping, and unreported garbage piles. These issues harm the environment, spread diseases, and diminish the quality of life in local communities.&#13;
&#13;
While many people want to help, there’s no easy, transparent, or motivating platform to report such issues or track whether action was taken.&#13;
Municipal bodies, on the other hand, often lack real-time visibility of waste hotspots, making it difficult to prioritize clean-ups efficiently.&#13;
&#13;
This is not just an Indian problem — many urban and rural areas across the world face similar issues, especially in fast-growing regions.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>CleanConnect - Turning awareness into action for a cleaner planet.</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong> This is how ServiceNow products could be useful : </strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>App Engine Studio:</strong> To build the “Report Issue” app where users can submit photos, descriptions, and locations of waste/hazard incidents.</li><li><strong>Service Portal:</strong> For citizen access and interaction - an easy, mobile-friendly interface to post and view reports.</li><li><strong>Flow Designer &amp; IntegrationHub:</strong> To automatically route reports to the right department or city zone, merge duplicate issues, and send status notifications.</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics / Dashboards:</strong> To visualize waste hotspots, track cleanup SLAs, and publish public cleanliness scorecards.</li><li><strong>Incident / Task Management:</strong> To assign clean-up or inspection tasks to field teams and close them upon completion.</li><li><strong>Notification Engine:</strong> To inform citizens when their report is being worked on or resolved.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Integration with mapping/geolocation APIs (for pinpointing and clustering waste reports).</li><li>Photo and video upload functionality for visual proof.</li><li>Optional AI-based image analysis to auto-classify waste type (plastic, organic, construction, etc.).</li><li>Municipal team directory and zone mapping for routing tasks.</li><li>Optional WhatsApp chatbot integration for areas with low app usage - allowing submissions via chat.</li><li>Optional integration with Swachh Bharat Mission APIs or global city sanitation systems for government use.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>User adoption:</strong> Citizens may initially hesitate to participate unless they see results or get recognition.</li><li><strong>Duplicate or false reports: </strong>Multiple users might post the same issue, or spam entries could occur.</li><li><strong>Limited municipal resources: </strong>Cleanup teams may not respond quickly if they are understaffed.</li><li><strong>Privacy and data protection:</strong> Managing photos, user data, and location information responsibly.</li><li><strong>Integration complexity:</strong> Connecting to various city or state systems (especially across different countries).</li><li><strong>Internet accessibility:</strong> Some rural areas may need offline or SMS-based reporting options.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-22 13:31:56</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>1d228d7c833032107980a6d0deaad38b</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>CleanConnect - Turning awareness into action for a cleaner planet.</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_1d228d7c833032107980a6d0deaad38b</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-22 13:32:00</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
