<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p><strong>ToxiTrace</strong> is an intelligent, real-time eco-toxicology platform that would:</p>
<p>Enable <strong>communities</strong> to understand local environmental risks and respond proactively.</p>
<p>Help <strong>industries</strong> self-monitor and prevent chemical overflows before legal thresholds are crossed.</p>
<p>Empower <strong>schools, farms, and public health agencies</strong> with early alerts to prevent exposure.</p>
<p>Support <strong>governments and NGOs</strong> in tracking pollution hotspots, enforcing regulations, and prioritizing clean-up.</p>
<p>Create <strong>transparency and accountability</strong> across polluters, protectors, and those most affected.</p>
<p>Ultimately, it could become the <strong>standard platform for eco-toxicology risk response</strong>, reducing environmental damage, preserving ecosystems, and improving human health outcomes.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>The global environment is increasingly impacted by eco-toxic pollutants: industrial chemicals, pesticides, microplastics, heavy metals, PFAS, and pharmaceutical waste. These toxins silently degrade ecosystems, water sources, food chains, and human health. Yet there is no centralized platform that tracks real-time eco-toxic exposure, links it to biodiversity and human risk, and provides early alerts or actionable insights to the people, industries, and institutions affected.&#13;
Currently, data exists in fragmented silos, environmental agencies, scientific journals, and industrial self-reporting tools, making it nearly impossible for communities, local governments, or industries to understand:&#13;
&#13;
What is being released into their environment?&#13;
&#13;
What impact it has on soil, water, wildlife, and public health?&#13;
&#13;
When and how to act before irreversible damage occurs?&#13;
&#13;
There is a massive gap between eco-toxicological science and real-time, actionable response.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>ToxiTrace — An Intelligent Eco-Toxicology Risk Management &amp; Alert System</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>ToxiTrace</strong> will be a ServiceNow-based application that acts as a <strong>central intelligence system</strong> for eco-toxicological exposure and response. Here&#39;s how it works:</li></ul>
<h4>1. <strong>Real-Time Eco-Toxicity Monitoring</strong></h4>
<ul><li>Pull data from open APIs (EPA, FAO, NASA, local water/air quality monitors)</li><li>Use location-based filters to monitor toxic chemical levels in air, soil, and water</li></ul>
<h4>2. <strong>AI-Powered Risk Assessment Engine</strong></h4>
<ul><li>Automatically assess data against WHO and EPA eco-toxicity thresholds</li><li>Score local eco-health per region (“ToxiScore” 0–100)</li><li>Predict risks to ecosystems, biodiversity, and humans.</li></ul>
<p><strong>3. Community &amp; Industry Dashboards</strong></p>
<ul><li>Communities see local exposure, warnings, and recommended actions</li><li>Industries monitor their chemical output, receive early alerts, and track regulatory compliance</li><li>Governments track region-wide trends and enforcement status</li></ul>
<p><strong>4</strong>. <strong>Automated Emergency Workflows</strong></p>
<ul><li>Trigger alerts to environmental officers, local leaders, or schools when thresholds are crossed</li><li>Activate response playbooks (e.g., Water Contamination Detected → Disable local intake pumps → Notify population) </li></ul>
<h4>5. <strong>Citizen &amp; NGO Reporting Tools</strong></h4>
<ul><li>Allow users to report eco-toxic events (e.g., fish kills, strange odors, dead crops)</li><li>Use geotagged reports to correlate with upstream pollution data</li></ul>
<h4>6. <strong>Biodiversity Impact Tracker</strong></h4>
<ul><li>Integrate with platforms like iNaturalist and GBIF to track declines in local flora and fauna</li><li>Show correlation between chemical exposure and ecological changes</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>ServiceNow Capabilities</strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>ITSM / CSM</strong>: Manage pollution incidents, community complaints, and response tasks</li><li><strong>Flow Designer</strong>: Automate eco-emergency response workflows (alerts, actions, reporting)</li><li><strong>IntegrationHub</strong>: Pull data from open environmental APIs (EPA, FAO, WHO, satellite feeds)</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics</strong>: Visualize eco-risk trends, generate real-time ToxiScore dashboards</li><li><strong>Vault</strong>: Securely store sensitive industry data, reports, and compliance records</li><li><strong>Virtual Agent</strong>: Help users understand their local risk level and recommended actions</li><li><strong>App Engine Studio</strong>: Allow local authorities or corporations to build custom modules or workflows</li><li><strong>AI/ML (Predictive Intelligence)</strong>: Correlate toxic chemical patterns with biodiversity or health events</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Primarily <strong>external data sources and IoT integration</strong>, such as:</p>
<ul><li>Government open data (EPA TRI, EU E-PRTR, WHO, etc.)</li><li>Environmental sensor networks (air/water quality APIs)</li><li>Agricultural chemical use data (e.g., pesticide registries)</li><li>Public biodiversity platforms (iNaturalist, GBIF)</li><li>Optional: satellite imagery APIs (NASA, Sentinel, etc.)</li></ul>
<p>Map integrations for spatial analysis (e.g., Google Maps or OpenStreetMap)</p>
<p>Secure cloud storage for sensitive community and industrial data</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>Data fragmentation</strong>: Environmental data is scattered and inconsistently formatted; building robust ingestion pipelines will be key</p>
<p><strong>Privacy &amp; industry resistance</strong>: Some companies may not want their pollution tracked publicly; secure, anonymized reporting options will help</p>
<p><strong>Public understanding</strong>: Eco-toxicology is complex, using a plain-language Virtual Agent and visual dashboards will be essential</p>
<p><strong>Sensor &amp; data availability in low-income regions</strong>: Offer offline or partner-based modes to help underserved areas benefit too</p>
<p><strong>Accuracy &amp; liability</strong>: Real-time risk assessments must be carefully calibrated to avoid false panic or legal exposure</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-17 23:36:26</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>9caf9d93832832106e90c070ceaad37a</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>ToxiTrace — An Intelligent Eco-Toxicology Risk Management &amp; Alert System</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_9caf9d93832832106e90c070ceaad37a</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-17 23:36:28</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
