<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li><strong>Improved public health awareness</strong>: Real-time alerts allow citizens to take precautions.</li><li><strong>Proactive interventions</strong>: Predictive analytics forecasts high pollution periods, enabling preventive measures.</li><li><strong>Faster administrative response</strong>: Automated alerts and trend insights help schools, hospitals, and local authorities act before incidents occur.</li><li><strong>Measurable reduction in exposure risk</strong>: Predictive trends allow better planning and targeted awareness campaigns.</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Air pollution is a growing health concern in urban and industrial areas. Citizens, schools, and hospitals often lack real-time visibility into air quality, and authorities struggle to respond proactively to dangerous pollution spikes. Delayed alerts can lead to health hazards, especially for vulnerable populations like children, the elderly, or people with respiratory conditions. Current monitoring is mostly reactive rather than predictive.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>AirQuality Guardian – Real-Time &amp; Predictive Community Air Monitoring</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>IntegrationHub</strong> – Integrate with IoT device and sensor data into ServiceNow.</li><li><strong>Flow Designer</strong> – automate alerts, notifications, and escalations.</li><li><strong>Predictive Intelligence / AI</strong> – analyze historical and real-time data to forecast pollution levels.</li><li><strong>Service Portal</strong> – dashboards showing real-time data, trends, and predictions.</li><li><strong>Now Assist (AI chatbot)</strong> – provides guidance and answers questions.</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics</strong> – track long-term trends and measure impact of interventions</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Reliable IoT air quality sensors with consistent network connectivity.</li><li>Historical air quality data to train predictive models.</li><li>APIs or middleware to integrate IoT streams with ServiceNow and predictive intelligence.</li><li>Notification channels (SMS, email, push notifications).</li><li>User directory for role-based access to dashboards and alerts.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Ensuring accurate and calibrated sensor data for reliable predictions.</li><li>Handling large volumes of IoT data and predictive analytics in ServiceNow efficiently.</li><li>Maintaining real-time and predictive alert accuracy.</li><li>Deployment, maintenance, and replacement of IoT devices.</li><li>Data privacy concerns for location-specific monitoring.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-10 10:45:38</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>e345767cc32c72105ae3ba2ed40131e4</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>AirQuality Guardian – Real-Time &amp; Predictive Community Air Monitoring</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_e345767cc32c72105ae3ba2ed40131e4</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-10 10:45:39</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
