<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li>Improved Student Wellbeing: Monitor and increase student satisfaction scores through regular feedback surveys and wellbeing assessments.</li><li>Faster Issue Resolution: Reduce average time to resolve student support cases (e.g., counseling, academic support, accessibility requests) by at least 30% compared to baseline.</li><li>Increased Engagement: Track and raise portal usage rates, with targets such as 60% of students actively engaging within the first semester.</li><li>Data-Driven Insights: Provide educators and administrators with actionable analytics, including trends in student concerns, service utilization, and at-risk student identification, enabling targeted interventions.</li><li>Resource Optimization: Streamline support workflows, reducing redundant processes and enabling staff to focus on high-impact interactions.</li><li> </li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Develop a comprehensive portal where students can access mental health resources, request counseling appointments, report concerns, and find support groups. Automate the process of connecting students to the right services and professionals, ensuring timely interventions and support.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Student Support and Wellbeing Portal</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Case and Knowledge Management: Centralizes student requests and support documentation, automating routing and escalation for timely intervention.</li><li>HR Service Delivery (HRSD): Adapts HRSD modules for student-centric services such as counseling appointments, academic accommodations, and wellbeing check-ins.</li><li>Virtual Agent: Enables 24/7 self-service through AI-powered chatbots for common queries, appointment bookings, and resource navigation.</li><li>IntegrationHub: Connects the portal with external systems like student information systems (SIS), learning management systems (LMS), and communication platforms (email, SMS, mobile apps).</li><li>Performance Analytics: Provides dashboards and reports for real-time tracking of student issues, support response times, and engagement metrics.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Integrations: Secure connections to SIS, LMS, and campus communication tools to ensure seamless data flow and unified user experiences.</li><li>Data Sources: Access to anonymized student records, support history, and feedback for personalized and efficient support.</li><li>Infrastructure: Scalable ServiceNow instance with adequate licensing, data storage, and security measures to support user volume and sensitive data.</li><li>Authentication: Integration with institutional single sign-on (SSO) systems to ensure secure and convenient access for students and staff.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Data Privacy and Compliance: Ensuring strict adherence to data protection regulations (e.g., FERPA, GDPR) regarding student information and support records.</li><li>User Adoption: Encouraging both students and staff to adopt the portal through targeted change management, training, and incentives.</li><li>Integration Complexity: Managing technical challenges in connecting disparate systems and maintaining data integrity across platforms.</li><li>Scalability: Designing processes and infrastructure to accommodate growth in user numbers and expanding support services without performance degradation.</li><li>Resource Alignment: Coordinating with IT, counseling, and academic teams to ensure timely portal setup, configuration, and ongoing support.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-26 12:00:35</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>30af59ca53347210f0ad17c0a0490e89</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Student Support and Wellbeing Portal</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_30af59ca53347210f0ad17c0a0490e89</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-26 12:00:36</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
