<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ol><li>Reduce emergency response time by 50% through real-time resource visibility</li><li>Eliminate 70% of duplicate efforts across responding organizations</li><li>Provide real-time needs assessment to identify underserved areas</li><li>Track 100% of donations and resources from source to beneficiary</li><li>Enable data-driven decision making for resource allocation</li><li>Improve coordination between 10&#43; agencies in a disaster zone</li></ol>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>During disasters and emergencies, multiple agencies, nonprofits, and volunteers attempt to coordinate relief efforts, but lack a unified system to track available resources, identify gaps, and prevent duplication. This leads to some areas being over-served while others are neglected, wasted resources, and delayed response times that can cost lives.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Crisis Resource Coordination Hub</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>IT Operations Management (adapted for disaster operations)<br />Service Operations Workspace for coordination teams<br />Virtual Agent for citizen self-service requests<br />Now Mobile for field workers<br />Performance Analytics and dashboards<br />GeoMaps for visualization<br />Integration Hub for connecting emergency services<br />Predictive Intelligence for anticipating resource needs</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>GIS/mapping services integration<br />Weather and hazard data feeds<br />Emergency alert systems (FEMA, local emergency services)<br />Communication platforms (SMS, radio systems)<br />Offline capability for areas without internet<br />Integration with 911/emergency dispatch systems</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>Getting multiple competing organizations to use a shared platform</li><li>Ensuring system reliability during high-stress disaster scenarios</li><li>Data security and privacy for vulnerable populations</li><li>Training responders during non-disaster periods</li><li>Maintaining accurate, up-to-date resource inventories</li><li>Handling system access in areas with limited connectivity</li><li>Coordinating across different jurisdictions and authority levels</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-07 13:24:35</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>7d1d77ff835c7a50e4f75dc6feaad32f</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Crisis Resource Coordination Hub</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_7d1d77ff835c7a50e4f75dc6feaad32f</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-07 13:24:37</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
