<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A platform that tracks and rewards eco-friendly behavior can:</p>
<ul><li>Encourage residents to plant more trees and conserve resources.</li><li>Create a culture of sustainability within housing societies.</li><li>Provide data-driven insights to building committees.</li><li>Offer recognition and incentives to top contributors.</li></ul>
<p><strong>Measurable outcomes:</strong></p>
<ul><li>500&#43; plants donated in the first 3 months.</li><li>20% reduction in electricity and water usage across participating homes.</li><li>Increased community participation in green initiatives.</li><li>Enhanced resident satisfaction and committee engagement.</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>In urban societies, environmental efforts like planting trees, saving electricity, and conserving water often go unnoticed and unappreciated. Residents lack motivation to adopt eco-friendly habits due to the absence of recognition or incentives. Building committees also struggle to track and reward such contributions effectively.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>GreenRank – Eco-Friendly Community Recognition Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>Service Portal</strong> – for resident registration, logging plant donations, and viewing rankings</li><li><strong>Record Producer</strong> – to collect user details and eco-friendly activity logs</li><li><strong>Flow Designer</strong> – to automate weekly ranking calculations and notifications</li><li><strong>Virtual Agent</strong> – for eco-tips, guidance, and engagement</li><li><strong>Notification Engine</strong> – to alert users about their rank, offers, and weekly updates</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics</strong> – to track contributions, resource usage, and community impact</li><li><strong>IntegrationHub</strong> – for optional integration with smart meters or utility APIs</li><li><strong>Survey Management</strong> – for collecting feedback and improving the platform</li><li><strong>Now Mobile (optional)</strong> – for mobile logging and updates</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Integration with smart meters or utility APIs for electricity/water usage tracking</li><li>Secure handling of resident data and activity logs</li><li>Notification system for real-time updates and recognition</li><li>Dynamic ranking logic based on multiple eco-metrics</li><li>Optional integration with committee billing systems for applying discounts</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Ensuring accurate and fair tracking of eco-friendly activities</li><li>Encouraging consistent participation from residents</li><li>Managing data privacy and secure access</li><li>Coordinating with building committees for incentives and billing adjustments</li><li>Scaling the platform across multiple societies or regions</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-24 11:32:36</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>95570bdd83b4b2102bb16f60ceaad392</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>GreenRank – Eco-Friendly Community Recognition Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_95570bdd83b4b2102bb16f60ceaad392</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-24 11:32:38</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
