<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ol><li>
<p><strong>Enhanced Employee Experience:</strong> Employees can easily view, book, or request parking slots through a self-service portal, reducing daily frustration and saving time.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Streamlined Management Operations:</strong> The administration team can efficiently allocate, monitor, and update parking slots using automated workflows in ServiceNow.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Increased Transparency and Accountability:</strong> A centralized system ensures every parking-related request or issue is tracked, resolved, and auditable.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Optimized Utilization of Parking Space:</strong> Real-time visibility into slot availability and usage helps in making data-driven decisions, avoiding under- or over-utilization.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Reduced Manual Effort and Errors:</strong> Automation minimizes human intervention in managing parking data, improving accuracy and overall operational efficiency.</p>
</li></ol>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>In many organizations, employees often face challenges related to parking management. Common issues include difficulty finding available parking spaces, confusion about assigned parking slots, and the inability to easily request changes or report problems with parking facilities.&#13;
&#13;
On the other hand, the management team struggles to efficiently allocate parking slots, track occupancy, and handle employee requests in a systematic way. The current manual or semi-digital processes often lead to delays, miscommunication, and inefficient use of available parking resources.&#13;
&#13;
These challenges create frustration among employees, increase administrative workload, and reduce overall operational efficiency within the organization.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>ParkNow: Smart Parking Management System</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>Service Catalogs</strong><br />We will create service catalogs for employees to request new parking slots or change their existing parking assignments.</p>
<p><strong>Record Producers</strong><br />We will use record producers specifically for raising parking-related issues, so employees can quickly report problems through the Service Portal or Mobile Portal.</p>
<p><strong>Custom Tables</strong><br />Custom tables will store all relevant data, including parking slots, employee assignments, request history, and issue tracking.</p>
<p><strong>Notifications</strong><br />Notifications will be configured to alert employees and management about request status, approvals, or any changes in real time.</p>
<p><strong>Automated Flows</strong><br />Flows will be designed using Flow Designer to automate the entire process, including approvals, slot allocation, and notifications, minimizing manual effort.</p>
<p><strong>Reports and Dashboards</strong><br />Reports and dashboards will provide management with real-time insights into parking utilization, pending requests, and overall system performance, enabling data-driven decisions.</p>
<p><strong>Mobile Portal</strong><br />The solution will also support a mobile portal, so employees can conveniently submit requests, check slot availability, and track their requests from anywhere.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>ServiceNow Platform</strong><br />The solution depends on a ServiceNow instance with access to the necessary modules like Service Portal, Flow Designer, and Reporting.</p>
<p><strong>Custom Tables and Data Schema</strong><br />Proper creation and configuration of custom tables to store parking slots, employee assignments, request history, and issue tracking are required.</p>
<p><strong>Record Producers and Service Catalogs</strong><br />The solution relies on Service Catalogs and Record Producers being correctly configured to handle requests and issues.</p>
<p><strong>Notifications</strong><br />Email or in-platform notification configurations must be set up for real-time alerts to employees and management.</p>
<p><strong>User Roles and Access Control</strong><br />Appropriate user roles, permissions, and access control rules must be defined to ensure employees and management can access the portal and perform their tasks securely.</p>
<p><strong>Mobile Portal</strong><br />If mobile access is required, the Service Portal must be optimized for mobile devices, including responsive design and mobile-friendly layouts.</p>
<p><strong>Flow Designer Dependencies</strong><br />Automation flows rely on correctly configured triggers, approvals, and notifications; any missing dependency can disrupt the automated process.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Ensuring <strong>accurate and up-to-date data</strong> for parking slots and employee assignments.</p>
<p>Designing <strong>flows and automation</strong> that handle all possible request scenarios without errors.</p>
<p>Configuring <strong>notifications</strong> to reach the right users at the right time.</p>
<p>Managing <strong>user roles and access controls</strong> securely and correctly.</p>
<p>Optimizing the <strong>Service Portal and Mobile Portal</strong> for smooth and user-friendly experience.</p>
<p>Integrating <strong>reporting and dashboards</strong> to provide meaningful insights without performance issues.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-07 17:50:34</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>63d9784483243210cb3c9610feaad3ec</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>ParkNow: Smart Parking Management System</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_63d9784483243210cb3c9610feaad3ec</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-07 17:50:36</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
