<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A ServiceNow-based ocean cleanup operations platform would increase plastic collection efficiency by 40-60% through AI-optimized routing, reduce equipment downtime through predictive maintenance, enable real-time coordination of multiple cleanup vessels and river interceptors, provide transparent impact metrics to donors and partners, and accelerate progress toward removing 90% of floating ocean plastic by 2040. The platform would manage the entire cleanup lifecycle from plastic detection to extraction to impact reporting</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Over 170 trillion plastic particles pollute the world's oceans, with 80% flowing from just 1,000 rivers globally. Ocean cleanup organizations and river interceptor programs struggle with coordinating deployment locations, tracking collection efficiency, managing maintenance schedules for cleanup equipment, optimizing vessel routes in real-time based on plastic concentration data, and measuring impact across multiple cleanup sites. Current systems lack integration between ocean monitoring data, field operations, equipment maintenance, and donor reporting, leading to suboptimal resource allocation and missed cleanup opportunities.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>OceanGuard Ops - Ocean Plastic Interceptor Operations Hub</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The platform would include: </p>
<p>1. Operations Dashboard - real-time map showing plastic concentration hotspots, active cleanup vessels, river interceptor status, and collection metrics.</p>
<p>2. AI Route Optimizer - uses satellite data, ocean current models, and historical collection data to recommend optimal cleanup paths that maximize plastic recovery.</p>
<p>3. Asset Management - tracks all cleanup equipment (vessels, interceptors, collection booms) with predictive maintenance alerts. </p>
<p>4. Field Worker Mobile App - allows crew to log collection data, equipment issues, and ocean conditions.</p>
<p>5. Donor Impact Portal - automated reports showing plastic removed by location, environmental impact (CO2 avoided, marine life protected), and project milestones.</p>
<p>The system would integrate with satellite imagery APIs (NASA, Sentinel), ocean monitoring sensors, and use Predictive Intelligence to forecast high-concentration areas and optimize fleet deployment. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>ServiceNow Products/Capabilities used:<br />App Engine Studio, IT Operations Management (ITOM), IoT Intelligence, Field Service Management, Mobile App Builder, Integration Hub, Predictive Intelligence for route optimization, Performance Analytics, GIS Connector </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>ServiceNow IT Operations Management (ITOM) for equipment monitoring and predictive maintenance</li><li>Integration Hub for satellite imagery APIs (NASA, Copernicus Sentinel), ocean current data, and IoT sensors on cleanup equipment</li><li>GIS mapping integration for visualizing plastic concentrations and cleanup routes</li><li>Mobile App Builder for crew data collection at sea</li><li>Predictive Intelligence for route optimization and equipment failure prediction</li><li>Performance Analytics for impact dashboards and donor reporting</li><li>Field Service Management for vessel and equipment maintenance scheduling</li><li>API connections to weather services and maritime traffic systems</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Ensuring reliable satellite data integration and real-time ocean monitoring, managing equipment connectivity in remote ocean locations, coordinating multiple organizations and vessels across international waters, and validating AI routing recommendations with oceanography experts would probably be the challenges in implementing this idea.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-20 03:44:47</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>dd45b04493f076104a52385efaba1043</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>OceanGuard Ops - Ocean Plastic Interceptor Operations Hub</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_dd45b04493f076104a52385efaba1043</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-20 03:44:48</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
