<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>The Community Food Share Network can significantly reduce food waste while improving food accessibility for vulnerable populations. By automating and centralizing the donation process, communities can:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Reduce food waste by up to 30%</strong> through faster, data-driven redistribution of surplus food.</li><li><strong>Support thousands of meals per week</strong> for families, shelters, and schools in need.</li><li><strong>Cut</strong><strong> coordination time by 60%</strong> through automated matching, pickup scheduling, and notifications.</li><li><strong>Increase transparency and accountability</strong> with real-time tracking of donations, deliveries, and impact analytics.</li><li><strong>Promote sustainability and community engagement</strong>, empowering local businesses and volunteers to participate in social good initiatives.</li></ul>
<p>By leveraging ServiceNow’s automation, workflow, and analytics capabilities, this solution can create a measurable, sustainable impact that strengthens community resilience and reduces hunger at scale.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Problem or Challenge:&#13;
Every day, tons of edible food are discarded by restaurants, grocery stores, schools, and households — while millions of people struggle with hunger. The gap isn’t due to a lack of resources, but a lack of coordination and visibility. Existing food donation efforts are often manual, fragmented, and rely on phone calls or spreadsheets, making it difficult to match surplus food with those who need it most in real time.&#13;
&#13;
Communities need a centralized, transparent, and automated way to connect food donors with recipients efficiently and safely — minimizing waste and maximizing social good.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Community Food Share Network</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The ideal solution is a <strong>centralized, ServiceNow-powered platform</strong> that seamlessly connects food donors with recipients and volunteers in real time. Key features include:</p>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>Intuitive Service Portal:</strong> Donors can quickly log surplus food availability, including quantity, type, and pickup timing. Recipients can request needed items.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Automated Matching &amp; Workflow:</strong> The system automatically matches available donations with nearby recipients based on type, quantity, and urgency.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Scheduling &amp; Logistics:</strong> Pickup and delivery tasks are automatically assigned to volunteers or delivery partners, with route optimization to reduce delays.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Notifications &amp; Tracking:</strong> Donors, recipients, and volunteers receive real-time notifications for status updates. Each donation is tracked end-to-end to ensure accountability.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Analytics &amp; Reporting:</strong> The platform measures metrics such as food saved, meals provided, volunteer engagement, and community impact to continuously improve the program.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Mobile Access:</strong> Volunteers and field workers can access the system on mobile devices to manage pickups, confirm deliveries, and update status on the go.</p>
</li></ol>
<p>This solution ensures that <strong>food reaches those in need quickly and efficiently</strong>, reduces waste, increases community collaboration, and provides actionable insights for decision-makers.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>1. ServiceNow Platform Features:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Service Portal for donor and recipient interaction.</li><li>Flow Designer for automated matching, notifications, and task assignments.</li><li>Field Service Management (FSM) for pickup and delivery scheduling.</li><li>Performance Analytics for impact tracking.</li></ul>
<p><strong>2. Integration Dependencies:</strong></p>
<ul><li><strong>Mapping/Logistics APIs</strong> (e.g., Google Maps, Mapbox) for route optimization and location-based matching.</li><li>Optional integration with external nonprofit or shelter databases for real-time recipient data.</li></ul>
<p><strong>3. User Access &amp; Authentication:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Single Sign-On (SSO) or other authentication mechanisms for donors, volunteers, and recipients.</li></ul>
<p><strong>4. Mobile Access:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Now Mobile app configuration for volunteers and field personnel to update donation statuses on the go.</li></ul>
<p><strong>5. Data Management:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Accurate tracking of inventory, food types, quantities, and expiry to ensure safety and accountability.</li></ul>
<p><strong>6. Compliance &amp; Security:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Adherence to food safety regulations and privacy requirements for participant information.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>1. Data Accuracy &amp; Timeliness:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Ensuring donors accurately report food quantity, type, and expiration dates.</li><li>Matching donations with recipients in real time to prevent food spoilage.</li></ul>
<p><strong>2. Volunteer &amp; Logistics Management:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Coordinating volunteers or delivery partners efficiently, especially during peak times.</li><li>Optimizing routes for pickups and deliveries to minimize delays.</li></ul>
<p><strong>3. Onboarding &amp; Adoption:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Encouraging restaurants, grocery stores, and community organizations to adopt the platform.</li><li>Training users on ServiceNow portal usage and mobile app features.</li></ul>
<p><strong>4. Compliance &amp; Safety:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Adhering to food safety regulations during collection, storage, and delivery.</li><li>Ensuring liability coverage for donors, volunteers, and recipients.</li></ul>
<p><strong>5. Scalability &amp; Performance:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Managing increasing volume of donations and requests as the platform grows.</li><li>Maintaining fast response times for matching, notifications, and mobile updates.</li></ul>
<p><strong>6. Privacy &amp; Security:</strong></p>
<ul><li>Protecting sensitive information about donors, volunteers, and recipients.</li><li>Ensuring secure access and data storage in compliance with regulations.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-08 01:46:32</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>67d42a8083ecb21095495dc6feaad39c</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Community Food Share Network</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_67d42a8083ecb21095495dc6feaad39c</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-08 01:46:34</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
