<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li>
<p><strong>40–70% reduction</strong> in vaccine spoilage through real-time monitoring and automated dispatch.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>30–50% faster repair response times</strong> for cold-chain assets.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Higher immunization coverage</strong> through reliable stock and cold-chain integrity.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Improved accountability</strong> and transparency across donors, NGOs, and ministries of health.</p>
</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>In many rural and low-resource communities, vaccines and essential medicines spoil before reaching patients due to unreliable cold-chain systems, power outages, and slow maintenance response times.&#13;
When a refrigerator or cold box fails, field health workers often lack visibility until doses are already wasted. Manual temperature logging and delayed reporting result in lost vaccines, reduced immunization rates, and public health setbacks.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>VillageReach-  Cold-Chain &amp; Community Vaccine Logistics</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>
<p><strong>App Engine Studio</strong> – for building custom modules such as vaccine inventory records, cold-box asset tracking, and clinic profiles.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>IT Operations Management (ITOM)</strong> – to monitor connected cold-chain assets through IoT device integrations, detect temperature anomalies, and trigger incident creation.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Field Service Management (FSM)</strong> – to automatically dispatch technicians based on skill, proximity, and availability when maintenance or repair is required.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Customer Service Management (CSM)</strong> – to handle communication between warehouses, clinics, and NGO coordinators for supply requests, recalls, and service updates.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>IntegrationHub</strong> – to connect external IoT platforms, SMS gateways, health systems (e.g., DHIS2, OpenLMIS), and mapping APIs for seamless data exchange.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Performance Analytics</strong> – to provide real-time dashboards showing temperature compliance, repair times, vaccine wastage, and coverage by region.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Flow Designer</strong> – to automate alerts, escalation workflows, and data synchronization across modules.</p>
</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>
<p><strong>IoT sensor APIs</strong> (temperature/humidity transmitters on cold boxes).</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>SMS or mobile gateways</strong> for alerts in low-connectivity areas.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>GIS/mapping API</strong> (e.g., Google Maps, Mapbox) for technician routing and clinic locations.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>IntegrationHub connectors</strong> to health logistics or donor reporting systems (DHIS2, OpenLMIS).</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Cloud data stream (MQTT, AWS IoT, or Azure IoT Hub)</strong> for telemetry ingestion.</p>
</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>
<p>Ensuring IoT reliability and battery life in remote environments.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Calibrating sensors across multiple device vendors.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Offline-first mobile app design for rural areas with low bandwidth.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Building capacity among local technicians and health workers for system upkeep.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Protecting data privacy and integrity across NGO and government layers.</p>
</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-16 05:18:11</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>d324a8fac36cf210b202be3ed4013124</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>VillageReach-  Cold-Chain &amp; Community Vaccine Logistics</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_d324a8fac36cf210b202be3ed4013124</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-16 05:18:12</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
