<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>no</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li>Facilitate 500&#43; mentorship pairs in first year (mentor-mentee)</li><li>Increase retention of women in tech learning programs by 50%</li><li>Increase job placements or internships for mentees by 30%</li><li>Trackable improvement in technical certifications achieved</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Though there's a growing interest among Nigerian women to enter technology (coding, ServiceNow, data, cloud), mentorship, structured learning paths, exposure to projects, and networking are often ad hoc. There is no unified, data-driven platform to register mentorship, track skill acquisition, manage learning outcomes, or connect with corporate opportunities. Beginners get lost; organizations duplicate efforts; female talent is under-leveraged.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>SheTech Connect – Women in Tech Mentorship &amp; Learning Portal</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>SheTech Connect would be a holistic learning &amp; mentorship ecosystem:</p>
<ul><li><strong>App Engine Studio:</strong> user profiles (mentors, mentees), learning module catalog, skill goals, and assessment logs.</li><li><strong>SPM / Strategic Portfolio Management:</strong> for planning learning portfolios, scheduling courses, and tracking progress over time, especially useful for enterprises wanting to partner or sponsor.</li><li><strong>Virtual Agent / GenAI:</strong> for automated Q&amp;A (“Which learning path is good for me?” and “Suggest local workshops”), maybe adaptive suggestions.</li><li><strong>Flow Designer:</strong> matching algorithm for mentors and mentees based on skills, location, and availability; automated scheduling; reminders.</li><li><strong>IntegrationHub:</strong> link with external course providers (Udemy, Coursera, LinkedIn Learning) to pull course metadata, maybe certifications, and also job boards.</li><li><strong>Performance Analytics:</strong> dashboards for how many women have taken courses and completed them and how many internships/jobs they move into; gender parity metrics.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Course provider APIs (or at least metadata), Email/SMS/WhatsApp gateway for notifications, and secure identity and profile management will be needed.</p>
<p>Gamification/reward systems (badges, certificates) and local community event integration are dependable but optional.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li><strong>Maintaining mentor availability &amp; quality:</strong> mentors might drop off; ensuring mentor commitment; vetting.</li><li><strong>Motivating mentees:</strong> avoiding early dropout; ensuring meaningful projects.</li><li><strong>Digital divide:</strong> many women may not have reliable internet or devices; they need mobile-friendly and low-bandwidth options.</li><li><strong>Localization:</strong> content might need local context; offer in local languages; reflect Nigeria’s tech job market.</li></ul>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-17 15:32:12</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>7cb87b03c3a83210a77f7c2ed401311a</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>SheTech Connect – Women in Tech Mentorship &amp; Learning Portal</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_7cb87b03c3a83210a77f7c2ed401311a</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-17 15:32:13</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
