<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>no</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>The impacts this will have: </p>
<p>By implementing a proactive maintenance and incident management system, solar energy utilization can be increased. This system will automatically detect faults or performance drops in solar panels or batteries, and create an incident in ServiceNow. Another impact will be a reduction in grid dependency and energy costs, due to transparent reporting on energy savings and carbon offset metrics. Automated dispatch will also improve response time to solar infrastructure issues through automated workflows. Another value is a knowledge base, as common technical problems are automatically documented, reducing ticket volume and improving overall customer support.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>With the growing demand for alternative energy sources, solar panel installations are becoming increasingly common across organizations, communities, and households. However, most lack centralized tools to monitor energy production, storage, and consumption. This gap leads to inefficiencies, underutilized capacity, and missed opportunities for optimization, maintenance, and sustainability reporting.  As a result, solar systems often suffer from delayed fault detection, limited visibility into performance metrics,  and fragmented support workflows.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>SolarSync:  Solar panel Monitoring and Optimization Platform </project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>ESG: To log and report renewable energy metrics aligned with sustainability goals.<br />ITSM: To manage solar panel maintenance, outages, and upgrades through automated workflows.<br />Performance Analytics: Used to visualize solar energy generation, battery storage, consumption usage, and trends.<br />IntegrationHub: Used to connect solar panel APIs, smart meters, and battery systems.<br />CMDB: To track and map solar panel assets, installation locations, and lifecycle status.<br />Field Service Management: Used to dispatch technicians.<br />Service Portal: Provides users with dashboards, FAQs, and self-service support.<br /> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>IOT-enabled solar panels or sensors that transmit data</p>
<p>APIs from solar panel and battery manufacturers.</p>
<p>Smart meters for real-time system readings.</p>
<p>Mobile devices for field technicians</p>
<p>Cloud storage facilities.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Ensuring data security for transmissions from panels to ServiceNow.</p>
<p>Connectivity challenge, particularly in rural or remote areas with limited network infrastructure.</p>
<p>Sensor compatibility and integration challenges may arise, as not all solar panels support standardized data interfaces or IoT connectivity.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-25 11:06:13</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>bb6337e553343610a9c8d7f0a0490e6d</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>SolarSync:  Solar panel Monitoring and Optimization Platform </sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_bb6337e553343610a9c8d7f0a0490e6d</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-25 11:06:15</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
