<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>sustainability</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A ServiceNow-based urban heat mitigation coordination platform would reduce urban temperatures by 5-8°F in targeted neighborhoods through strategic deployment of cooling technologies, decrease heat-related deaths by 40% in vulnerable communities, reduce energy consumption for air conditioning by 25-30%, lower air pollution levels, provide equity-focused heat mitigation by prioritizing underserved neighborhoods, enable cross-department coordination of cooling infrastructure projects, track ROI and effectiveness of different mitigation technologies, and guide long-term climate adaptation planning for cities globally.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Urban Heat Islands (UHI) cause cities to be 2-10°F warmer than surrounding rural areas, increasing heat-related deaths, energy consumption for cooling, and air pollution. Low-income communities and communities of color experience disproportionately higher temperatures due to less investment in trees, parks, and reflective infrastructure. &#13;
&#13;
Cities worldwide face challenges in strategically deploying UHI mitigation technologies—green roofs, cool pavements, tree canopy expansion, reflective coatings—due to lack of coordinated planning, inability to prioritize high-impact locations, difficulty tracking effectiveness of interventions, fragmented responsibility across departments (parks, transportation, buildings), and insufficient data on community-level heat exposure. Without systematic coordination, cities make ad-hoc cooling infrastructure decisions that fail to maximize impact on vulnerable populations.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>CoolCity Navigator - Urban Heat Island Cooling Infrastructure Manager</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The platform would include:</p>
<p>1. Heat Vulnerability Map - GIS-based dashboard showing real-time temperature data overlaid with demographic information to identify high-risk neighborhoods.</p>
<p>2. Mitigation Project Manager - tracks green roof installations, tree planting campaigns, cool pavement projects, and reflective coating applications with scheduling, budgets, and contractor management.</p>
<p>3. Equity Prioritization Engine - AI-powered scoring system that ranks potential project locations based on temperature data, population vulnerability (elderly, low-income, chronic illness), existing infrastructure gaps, and cost-effectiveness.</p>
<p>4. Asset Tracking - inventory of all cooling infrastructure (trees, green roofs, cool surfaces) with maintenance schedules and performance monitoring.</p>
<p>5. Impact Dashboard - before/after temperature comparisons, energy savings calculations, health outcome improvements, and carbon emission reductions.</p>
<p>6. Cross-Department Workflow - coordinates Parks Department (tree planting), Transportation (cool pavements), Buildings (green/cool roofs), and Public Health (heat emergency response). The system would integrate with weather APIs, IoT temperature sensors deployed across the city, satellite thermal imagery, and energy utility data to measure real-world impact. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>ServiceNow Products/Capabilities:<br />App Engine Studio, IT Asset Management, Project Portfolio Management, GIS Connector, Integration Hub, Mobile App Builder, Predictive Intelligence for heat forecasting, Performance Analytics, Field Service Management for maintenance, IoT Intelligence for sensor data.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>ServiceNow IT Asset Management for cooling infrastructure inventory</li><li>GIS mapping integration with real-time temperature data overlays</li><li>Integration Hub for weather APIs, IoT temperature sensors, satellite thermal imagery (NASA LANDSAT), and utility energy consumption data</li><li>Predictive Intelligence to forecast heat waves and recommend preemptive interventions</li><li>Project Portfolio Management for coordinating multiple mitigation projects across departments</li><li>Mobile App Builder for field workers to document installations and maintenance</li><li>Performance Analytics for measuring temperature reductions and ROI</li><li>Integration with demographic and health data (respecting privacy regulations)</li><li>Carbon footprint calculation for energy savings and emission reductions</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Integrating real-time temperature sensor networks across large cities, coordinating multiple city departments with different priorities and budgets, ensuring equitable distribution of cooling infrastructure to underserved communities, and validating long-term effectiveness of mitigation technologies would probably be the challenges in implementing this idea.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-20 07:23:33</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>9db62d0093bc76104a52385efaba10af</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>CoolCity Navigator - Urban Heat Island Cooling Infrastructure Manager</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_9db62d0093bc76104a52385efaba10af</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-20 07:23:36</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
