<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A centralized platform would help students access peer-verified study materials easily, reducing the financial burden of expensive textbooks and resources. Students would perform better academically by learning from others who succeeded in the same courses. The collaborative culture would strengthen as students help each other succeed. Over time, this could level the playing field between students who can afford expensive prep materials and those who can&#39;t.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>College students often struggle to find quality study materials from their peers who have already completed the same courses. Right now, students share notes through scattered group chats, emails, or social media, which makes it hard to find reliable materials when they need them. Many students also can't afford expensive textbooks and course materials, creating an unfair disadvantage. There's no organized way for students to contribute, discover, and rate study resources in one trusted place.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>StudyShare Network - Campus Study Resource Exchange</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>Students would log into a simple portal where they can browse study materials organized by department, course, and professor. They could search for specific topics or ask a virtual assistant to help them find what they need. When students upload their notes or study guides, others can rate them for quality, so the best materials naturally rise to the top. The platform would include discussion spaces where students can ask questions and collaborate. Students who contribute valuable content would earn recognition through badges or leaderboards, encouraging ongoing participation.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>ServiceNow Products/Capabilities used:<br />Service Portal for the student interface, Knowledge Management to organize and search study materials, Virtual Agent to help find resources through natural conversations, Service Catalog for requesting specific materials or tutoring connections, and Performance Analytics to track what courses need more resources. </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>The solution mainly uses built-in ServiceNow capabilities. We&#39;d need document storage for uploaded files and a content moderation process to review submissions. Optionally, we could add OCR technology to make handwritten notes searchable, but that&#39;s not essential for the initial version.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Keeping students engaged and contributing materials over time could be challenging. We&#39;d need clear guidelines to prevent sharing of exam answers or copyrighted textbook content. Quality control would require some level of moderation to ensure uploaded materials are actually helpful. Getting initial buy-in from students to start contributing would take some marketing effort.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-24 08:15:07</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>47199ad193b836104a52385efaba10d5</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>StudyShare Network - Campus Study Resource Exchange</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_47199ad193b836104a52385efaba10d5</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-24 08:15:08</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
