<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Potential Impact of the Technology Solution</strong></h2>
<p>The <strong>SafeHer</strong> solution has the potential to <strong>transform community safety</strong> by leveraging ServiceNow’s automation, workflows, and analytics capabilities to deliver faster, more transparent, and data-driven responses to women’s safety concerns.</p>
<h3><strong>1. Faster Emergency Response</strong></h3>
<p>Automated workflows connect victims, authorities, and responders in <strong>real-time</strong>, reducing manual coordination.</p>
<p><strong>Instant alerts</strong> to police, family members, and nearby help centers can <strong>cut average response time by up to 70%</strong>.</p>
<p>Geo-location sharing ensures responders can locate victims quickly and accurately.</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>2. Increased Reporting and Awareness</strong></h3>
<p>Anonymous reporting options and a user-friendly portal encourage women to <strong>report incidents safely</strong> without fear of exposure.</p>
<p>Data aggregation across cases builds <strong>public awareness</strong> about high-risk areas and peak times for incidents.</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>3. Improved Coordination Among Stakeholders</strong></h3>
<p>Centralized platform enables <strong>seamless collaboration</strong> between police departments, NGOs, and emergency responders.</p>
<p>Automated <strong>case routing, status updates, and SLAs</strong> ensure accountability at every step.</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>4. Data-Driven Safety Planning</strong></h3>
<p>Dashboards and analytics reveal <strong>patterns of incidents by time, location, and type</strong>, helping authorities deploy resources proactively.</p>
<p>Enables <strong>predictive policing and safety measures</strong>, such as increasing patrols or improving lighting in risk zones.</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>5. Enhanced Privacy and Trust</strong></h3>
<p>Role-based access and data encryption guarantee <strong>complete confidentiality</strong> of victim information.</p>
<p>Transparent case tracking builds <strong>public confidence</strong> in digital safety systems.</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>6. Empowerment and Community Engagement</strong></h3>
<p>Empowers women to <strong>take control of their safety</strong> through technology.</p>
<p>Promotes <strong>community participation</strong> — residents, organizations, and authorities can work together on verified data.</p>
<p>Contributes directly to <strong>UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDG 5: Gender Equality &amp; SDG 11: Sustainable Cities)</strong>.</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>7. Scalable &amp; Replicable Model</strong></h3>
<p>Once piloted in one city, the solution can be easily <strong>scaled nationwide</strong> or adapted for campuses, workplaces, and public spaces.</p>
<p>The platform can integrate with <strong>existing helpline systems</strong> and expand to include <strong>mental health or legal support</strong>.</p>
<div class="_tableContainer_1rjym_1">
<div class="group _tableWrapper_1rjym_13 flex w-fit flex-col-reverse">
<table class="w-fit min-w-(--thread-content-width)" style="width: 5.44394%;"><thead><tr><th style="width: 33.8241%;"> </th><th style="width: 33.8241%;"> </th><th style="width: 33.8241%;"> </th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td></tr><tr><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td></tr><tr><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td></tr><tr><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td></tr><tr><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td></tr><tr><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td><td style="width: 33.8241%;"> </td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>In cities across India and globally, women face daily safety concerns during travel, at workplaces, and even within communities.&#13;
Existing safety systems are fragmented — emergency numbers, complaint portals, and support services are scattered across different apps and departments, making response times slow and inconsistent.&#13;
&#13;
Many incidents go unreported due to fear, lack of anonymity, or uncertainty about where to seek help.&#13;
&#13;
SafeHer aims to provide a unified, secure, and anonymous platform for women to report safety incidents, request emergency help, access verified support centers, and track the status of their reports — all through ServiceNow.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>SafeHer — ServiceNow Application for Women’s Safety &amp; Emergency Support</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>Imagine a woman walking home late from work. She feels unsafe and opens the <strong>SafeHer mobile app</strong>. With just one tap on the <strong>SOS button</strong>, an alert is automatically sent to the <strong>nearest police station</strong>, <strong>her emergency contacts</strong>, and a <strong>verified NGO help center</strong> — all at once.</p>
<p>The system creates a <strong>case in ServiceNow</strong> with her live location, time, and type of incident. Authorities can track, respond, and update the case in real time. The woman can also <strong>report harassment or unsafe areas anonymously</strong>, without sharing her personal details.</p>
<p>Over time, all reported cases are analyzed on a <strong>dashboard</strong> to identify unsafe zones, helping the police and local bodies take preventive action — like improving street lighting or increasing patrols.</p>
<p>So, the ideal solution is a <strong>simple, fast, and connected system</strong> that helps women feel safe anywhere, anytime — using technology to bring <strong>trust, speed, and visibility</strong> into every safety response.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>The SafeHer solution depends on a few key technologies to function smoothly in real-life emergency situations:</p>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>ServiceNow Platform</strong> – Core foundation for building the app using App Engine, Case Management, and Flow Designer.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Mobile Access</strong> – So women can quickly send SOS alerts and track help using their phones through the ServiceNow Mobile App.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Location Tracking</strong> – Integration with GPS or Google Maps API to share the user’s exact location with nearby police or help centers.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Communication Channels</strong> – SMS, WhatsApp, or email setup to send instant alerts to family members and authorities.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>IntegrationHub Connections</strong> – To link with external emergency systems like police, hospital, or NGO databases.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Security Controls</strong> – Strong access rules and encryption to keep all user data private and protected.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Analytics Dashboard</strong> – For authorities to view trends, identify unsafe zones, and plan preventive actions.</p>
</li></ol>
<hr />
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p><strong>Building Trust and Awareness</strong> – Many women might hesitate to use a digital platform for safety due to fear or past experiences. It will take strong awareness campaigns and community partnerships to earn trust.</p>
<p><strong>Real-Time Coordination</strong> – Handling live alerts means the system must connect instantly with police, hospitals, and NGOs. Any delay or technical glitch could affect emergency response time.</p>
<p><strong>Data Sensitivity</strong> – The app will store highly confidential information like locations and personal details. Ensuring encryption, privacy, and secure access control is a top priority.</p>
<p><strong>Connectivity Gaps</strong> – In certain rural or low-signal areas, SOS alerts might not send immediately, so offline backup options (like SMS fallback) are important.</p>
<p><strong>Integration Complexity</strong> – Each city or region may have different emergency systems, helplines, and contact networks. Integrating them into one smooth workflow will take time and coordination.</p>
<p><strong>Operational Sustainability</strong> – After launch, maintaining updated contact databases, 24/7 monitoring, and user support requires long-term funding or partnerships with government agencies.</p>
<p><strong>Scalability</strong> – As more users and cities join, the system needs to handle thousands of cases without slowing down or losing accuracy.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-29 17:44:53</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>a0ea4a4b8338b210edbee5d0deaad31b</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>SafeHer — ServiceNow Application for Women’s Safety &amp; Emergency Support</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_a0ea4a4b8338b210edbee5d0deaad31b</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-29 17:44:54</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
