<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Centralized tracking of <strong>children’s profiles, education, and health records</strong></p>
<p><strong>Improved donor transparency</strong> and increased trust in organizations</p>
<p><strong>Faster allocation of resources</strong> (clothes, food, medicines) based on real-time needs</p>
<p>Measurable increase in donor retention and volunteer participation</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Many orphanages still depend on manual records to track children’s details, donations, medical needs, and educational progress. This causes data loss, missed support opportunities, and lack of transparency for donors and NGOs who want to help.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>HopeCare” — Orphanage Management and Support Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>A <strong>ServiceNow application</strong> that acts as a digital management system for orphanages.</p>
<p>Each child has a <strong>unique record</strong> with personal, health, and education details.</p>
<p>Donors and NGOs can view available donation requests (e.g., books, tuition, medical help).</p>
<p><strong>Automated notifications</strong> sent when urgent needs arise or new children are admitted.</p>
<p><strong>Reports and dashboards</strong> for orphanage administrators to track activities, donations, and well-being indicators.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>App Engine Studio</strong> — to build the core orphanage management app</p>
<p><strong>Flow Designer</strong> — to automate donation approvals and notifications</p>
<p><strong>Service Portal</strong> — for donors and volunteers to view needs and contribute</p>
<p><strong>Reporting &amp; Dashboards</strong> — for transparency and progress tracking</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>Integration with <strong>payment gateways</strong> (for online donations)</p>
<p>Optional: <strong>Google Sheets or NGO systems</strong> for data sync</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Data privacy for children’s personal and health details</p>
<p>Verifying legitimate orphanages and donors</p>
<p>Training staff to adopt a digital system</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-30 07:11:44</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>40d44d5783f4f210edbee5d0deaad34a</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>HopeCare” — Orphanage Management and Support Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_40d44d5783f4f210edbee5d0deaad34a</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-30 07:11:46</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
