<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A technology solution could help 10,000&#43; women and girls access free products in the first year.</p>
<p>It would educate 50,000&#43; people on women&#39;s health, help organizations track and reduce product waste by 30%, and provide data to show real impact and support future funding.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Millions of women and girls face period poverty - lacking access to affordable menstrual products - forcing them to miss school or use unsafe alternatives. 

At the same time, lack of proper health education and cultural shame create misinformation and silence, stopping people from getting the help and resources they need.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>EmpowerHer: Health Education &amp; Product Access</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>A mobile-friendly portal or app where users can find nearby free product locations, request supplies discreetly, and access health education in multiple languages.</li><li>ServiceNow&#39;s Service Portal for user access</li><li>Knowledge Management for educational content</li><li>Asset Management for inventory tracking</li><li>Virtual Agent for answering questions anonymously</li><li>Performance Analytics to measure impact and support decision-making.</li><li>SMS Services.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>SMS services for notifications in low-internet areas, mapping tools (like Google Maps) for location services, translation on multiple languages, privacy to protect user identity and connections to nonprofit systems, healthcare providers and donation platforms.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Cultural shame and stigma may prevent people from using the platform, many users in underserved areas may lack internet or smartphones, and keeping a steady supply of products with consistent funding would be difficult.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-21 10:07:02</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>acd55718c3f83e10325d38bc0501314a</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>EmpowerHer: Health Education &amp; Product Access</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_acd55718c3f83e10325d38bc0501314a</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-21 10:07:04</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
