<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<ul><li>Makes mental health support more accessible, private, and immediate</li><li>Uses Generative AI to provide empathetic, guided conversations to help users articulate their needs</li><li>Reduces crisis response time and ensures users are directed to the right support</li><li>Encourages early help-seeking behavior by making support feel approachable and safe</li><li>Enables data-driven insights to strengthen wellness programs</li></ul>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>People experiencing emotional distress or psychological crises hesitate to reach out for help&#13;
-Traditional support channels like email or static forms are not fast, engaging, or private enough&#13;
-Requests often get delayed or misrouted, leaving individuals without timely support&#13;
-People may not always know how to express what they’re going through or where to find the right resources&#13;
&#13;
There’s a strong need for a confidential, accessible, and intelligent platform that connects individuals to the right support channels quickly with personalized guidance and empathy.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Wellbeing Assist: Mental Health Support Hub</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Record Producer: Simple, user-friendly wellness request form</li><li>Flow Designer: Smart routing of requests to wellness, HR, or counseling teams</li><li>Notifications: Confidential alerts and updates to responders</li><li>App Engine Studio: Custom Wellness Request application</li><li>AI Search: Auto-suggest self-help content and relevant support resources</li><li>Generative AI: Provides empathetic conversation assistance, summarizes user input, and recommends next steps</li><li>Performance Analytics: Trend analysis and wellness program improvement insights</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Record Producer: Simple, user-friendly wellness request form.</li><li>Flow Designer: Smart routing of requests to wellness, HR, or counseling teams.</li><li>Notifications: Confidential alerts and updates to responders.</li><li>App Engine Studio: Custom Wellness Request application.</li><li>AI Search: Auto-suggest self-help content and relevant support resources.</li><li>Generative AI: Provides empathetic conversation assistance, summarizes user input, and recommends next steps.</li><li>Performance Analytics: Trend analysis and wellness program improvement insights.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Protecting sensitive and confidential user data with strict access controls</p>
<p>Ensuring AI responses remain empathetic, safe, and accurate</p>
<p>Balancing automation with human intervention for critical cases</p>
<p>Encouraging user trust and adoption of an AI-assisted mental health platform</p>
<p>Managing compliance with data privacy regulations and organizational policies</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-15 14:28:01</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>2e95596e83e0721010071f65eeaad3ea</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Wellbeing Assist: Mental Health Support Hub</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_2e95596e83e0721010071f65eeaad3ea</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-15 14:28:02</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
